<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reviews | Core dump overflow]]></title>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-11-30T16:39:16+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://chousensha.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[chousensha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social Engineering Expert course review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/11/11/social-engineering-expert-course-review/"/>
    <updated>2018-11-11T13:17:57+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/11/11/social-engineering-expert-course-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently taken the <a href="https://redteam-training.thinkific.com/courses/social-engineering-expert">Social Engineering Expert</a> from <a href="https://www.redteamsecure.com/">RedTeam Security</a>. If you don&rsquo;t know about them, check out their articles and videos about their engagements, they&rsquo;re doing some really cool stuff. In this post I will share my impressions about the course.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all, the author of the course is also the founder of RedTeam Security, Jeremiah Talamantes. He&rsquo;s authored a book called <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Social-Engineers-Playbook-Practical-Pretexting/dp/0692306617/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1452290969&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=social+engineers+playbook&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=talamantesus-20&amp;linkId=1f8b9cac92cdd16ae8d1956668d9942b">The Social Engineer’s Playbook: A Practical Guide to Pretexting</a>
, which I haven&rsquo;t tried yet. He is clearly very experienced and throughout the course, he&rsquo;s sharing various stories from the operations he&rsquo;s conducted.</p>

<p>The course is priced at 59$, but there are discounts every now and then. The training is video-based, where the instructor is sharing slides and talking about the topics. There are some valuable documents that can be downloaded, mainly templates and sample models for social engineering reports, plans and field notes guides. These can be used as starting points for your own operations.</p>

<p>As for the main structure of the course, it is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Introduction to social engineering</strong> &ndash; this covers the terminology around SE (it&rsquo;s getting tiring to type that) and goes through several examples</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Attack vectors</strong> &ndash; very useful section for actually conducting a SE campaign, it goes over different techniques and tools for social engineering your target, with actionable tips that you can use right away to enhance your operations. It also summarizes an attack in a very clear way, through the Social Engineering Kill Chain</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Methodology</strong> &ndash; this is another very practical section that covers planning and execution.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Information gathering</strong> &ndash; physical and digital techniques for information gathering. There is a gear list for physical reconaissance that makes for a good reference. However, I found the digital side to be under-represented, only Maltego and Metagoofill are discussed. I would have expected at least a breakdown of the SET functionality, and more demos about OSINT and conducting phishing campaigns.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Psychology &amp; manipulation</strong> &ndash; very applicable in day-to-day life, not limited to the field of security and SE, this describes various influencing and elicitation techniques that can be used to gain information or an expected behavior from a target. Not only that, but it also gives you awareness of such techniques being used on you.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Non-verbal communicaton</strong> &ndash; this is where micro expressions and body language are discussed. It essentially gives you a roadmap for reading people&rsquo;s true feelings and intentions, detecting lies, and masking your own thoughts. Very practical to be aware of these thing in all kinds of settings and social interactions.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All in all, I&rsquo;ve really enjoyed this course and highly recommend it. What would have made it even better would have been a practical component in order to complete it, a lab or task around phishing / OSINT, especially since at the end you get a certification. That being said, this is a very solid course and you don&rsquo;t need to be social engineered to get it :D</p>

<p>```</p>

<hr />

<p>/ Change your thoughts and you change \
\ your world.                         /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CCNA Cyber Ops review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/ccna-cyber-ops-review/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-09T10:11:41+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/ccna-cyber-ops-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cisco Cybersecurity Scholarship program has concluded for the first cohort, and I have been fortunate enough to make it into the program! Now that the course and 2 exams are over, and I have a brand new certification, I thought I&rsquo;d share some info about what is covered in the CCNA Cyber Ops study materials.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, I&rsquo;d like to thank Cisco for this amazing opportunity, and I wish more vendors would take their example. Yes, the latest exam price increase isn&rsquo;t nice, but this offering of a new certification&rsquo;s courses and exams to 10 000 people was an awesome move, especially for people who shared an interest in the security topics but wouldn&rsquo;t have gone to the certification path due to costs.</p>

<p>It also helped in bringing like-minded people together, creating communities and study groups over social media networks, and exchanging information about various security subjects.</p>

<p>So, what is this new CCNA that has the word &ldquo;cyber&rdquo; in it all about?</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/cyber.JPG" title="&lsquo;ccna cyber&rsquo; &lsquo;ccna cyber ops&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The certification aims to prepare people for working as security analysts in a Security Operations Center. This is a blue-team focused certification, and here are the skills that it covers:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/skills.JPG" title="&lsquo;ccna cyber skills&rsquo; &lsquo;ccna cyber ops skills&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The scholarship consisted of 3 courses that had to be completed within 3 months, free vouchers for the 2 exams, and access to forums and mentors.</p>

<p><strong>Introduction to cybersecurity</strong></p>

<p>The first course was a very basic introductory course on what cybersecurity is and why it is needed. You can take it for free from Cisco&rsquo;s Networking Academy. This was a prerequisite for starting the other 2 courses that actually made up the certification part.</p>

<p><strong>Understanding Cisco cybersecurity fundamentals</strong></p>

<p>This second course was a blast! 14 sections, massive amount of material, both writen and videos, lots of information covered, I really enjoyed it! Some of it was review for me, but I also learned plenty of new things about DHCP relays, the CAPWAP protocol, the Security Onion suite, which is like the Kali of defensive security, and much more! The cryptograhpy section was excellently explained, and the Linux chapter might as well be a course in itself. Here&rsquo;s a list with some of the topics:</p>

<ul>
<li>networking stuff, protocols, attacks, devices</li>
<li>cryptography &ndash; detailed and easy to understand</li>
<li>general infosec concepts</li>
<li>web attacks</li>
<li>Windows and Linux sections with commands, filesystem structure, the ways the OS works, etc.</li>
<li>network and host security</li>
<li>various types of security devices and logs</li>
<li>different types of models that deal with threats</li>
</ul>


<p>A great addition to the study materials were the labs, where you could play with various OSes and tools in your browser, simulate attacks and react to different scenarios. It took a while for the labs to be initialized, but there were also walkthroughs for doing the lab, or skipping it altogether and following the steps instead.</p>

<p>You can find the exam topics for this course at <a href="https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secfnd/exam-topics">https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secfnd/exam-topics</a></p>

<p><strong>Implementing Cisco cybersecurity operations</strong></p>

<p>This course wasn&rsquo;t as big as the previous one, it had 13 sections and 2 appendices. It built up on the foundation of the other one, focusing on various aspects of incident response. It felt a bit rushed though, as it could have covered more material instead of breezing through, and the amount of typos that I found in it was pretty high. But overall, it was a good follow-up, and it had links for many resources where you could learn more. Some of the topics covered are:</p>

<ul>
<li>types of SOCs, NSM tools and data</li>
<li>incident analysis and threat hunting</li>
<li>CVSS scoring</li>
<li>data manipulation, correlation and normalization</li>
<li>incident detection and playbooks</li>
<li>incident response and automation</li>
</ul>


<p>The biggest problem that I faced before the exam was that the exam topics didn&rsquo;t follow the course content. Here is the exam guide: <a href="https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secops/exam-topics">https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secops/exam-topics</a></p>

<p>Fortunately, the mentors assigned to us were very helpful, and in addition to hosting webinars that reinforced the study material, they put together some documents that followed the exam blueprint and filled the gaps in information.</p>

<p>Overall, this has been a very interesting experience and I am happy to have participated in it! Again, hats off to Cisco for making this program available to security enthusiasts, and happy threat hunting!</p>

<p>``` plain</p>

<hr />

<p>/ You worry too much about your job. Stop \
\ it. You are not paid enough to worry.   /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book review - Nmap Network Scanning]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2016/08/24/book-review-nmap-network-scanning/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-24T13:02:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2016/08/24/book-review-nmap-network-scanning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I have read the so-called Nmap bible, the Nmap Network Scanning book written by the creator of Nmap himself. I&rsquo;ve decided to make
a new section on the blog with the books I&rsquo;m reading and that I find most useful. Needless to say, this was a great book, that has upped my
Nmap game considerably. Right from the start, I highly recommend this as a book that should be in the arsenal of every pentester, system admin,
network engineer or plain old computer guy. The amount of information you get out of it is not constrained to a specific field.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nmap-Network-Scanning-Official-Discovery/dp/0979958717/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&linkCode=li2&tag=sensha10-20&linkId=791bdedacea7ac3bd1caea9852082708" target="_blank"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51BIsSMZqML._SX382_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg"/></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Contents</h1>

<p><strong>Ch. 1. Getting Started with Nmap</strong> &ndash; begins with some usage stories, and some legal information</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 2. Obtaining, Compiling, Installing, and Removing Nmap</strong> &ndash; continues with how to install Nmap on different operating systems</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 3. Host Discovery (Ping Scanning)</strong> &ndash; covers various host discovery techniques</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 4. Port Scanning Overview</strong> &ndash; all you want to know about port scanning</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 5. Port Scanning Techniques and Algorithms</strong> &ndash; port scanning techniques explained in more detail, along with their under-the-hood
implementations</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 6. Optimizing Nmap Performance</strong> &ndash; fine-tuning your scans for more speed</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 7. Service and Application Version Detection</strong> &ndash; all about the service detection capabilities of Nmap</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 8. Remote OS Detection</strong> &ndash; how Nmap performs OS detection</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 9. Nmap Scripting Engine</strong> &ndash; script creation and API information</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 10. Detecting and Subverting Firewalls and Intrusion Detection Systems</strong> &ndash; firewall evasion techniques</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 11. Defenses Against Nmap</strong> &ndash; defenses against Nmap scans</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 12. Zenmap GUI Users' Guide</strong> &ndash; presents the Nmap GUI interface</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 13. Nmap Output Formats</strong> &ndash; directing Nmap output to different file formats</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 14. Understanding and Customizing Nmap Data Files</strong> &ndash; working with some of the main internal Nmap files</p>

<p><strong>Ch. 15. Nmap Reference Guide</strong> &ndash; reference guide to Nmap commands</p>

<p>If you have enjoyed the Stealing the Network series, you will love this one! The style is similar, after all, Fyodor is also a
co-author of that amazing series. The book is sprinkled with fictional stories that illustrate the use of Nmap, along with backstories
of engagements the author has participated in, and case studies of users improving Nmap for certain tasks. All these stories contain great
advice not just on the technical side, but also on best practices. For example, Fyodor stresses the fact of always confirming that the IP range
you received for an engagement actually belongs to the target organization &ndash; or else you might end up  scanning the wrong target..like the army :&ndash;)</p>

<p>There are also plenty of funny comments and geeky stuff, from the friendly tip that &ldquo;using Nmap from your work or school computer to attack
banks and military targets is a bad idea&rdquo; and the technique and Nmap command that Trinity used to scan the Matrix, to life-changing
advice that says &ldquo;In life&rsquo;s bleakest moments when all hope seems to be lost, what should you turn to? Nmap, of course !&rdquo;. By the way, if you are curious,
the above mentioned scan against the Matrix was performed with <code>nmap -v -sS -0 10.2.2.2</code>. Fyodor also made a list on his site of other
movies that showcased the use of Nmap, which you can find at <a href="https://nmap.org/movies/">https://nmap.org/movies/</a></p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m sure that you want to hear about the actual content that will help turn you into a network scanning wizard. There are tons
of resources presented, not just related to Nmap, that can facilitate the information gathering process, such as DNS tools. Every Nmap command
is described in detail, with actual examples of using it, what happens under the hood when you run it, and  the situation where it will come
most in handy. All the command line switches are covered individually, but also in combinations, for comprehensive coverage of different scenarios.</p>

<p>The book also contains a good amount of TCP information and low-level details of both Nmap and network operations in general, along with
beautiful and detailed diagrams. There is information on scrips and how to create your own to enhance Nmap, and also description of the code itself.
At the end, there is a reference guide for all commands. While some of the content is a bit dated, you can get the whole up-to-date information
on the <a href="https://nmap.org/">https://nmap.org/</a> site, for free!</p>

<p>Finally, this awesome book was created with open source tools. Hats off to Fyodor&rsquo;s support to the open source community.</p>

<h3>Flash review</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>in-depth coverage of all Nmap commands, their internals and use cases</p></li>
<li><p>low-level networking internals, comprehensive overview of how Nmap operates in the network environment itself</p></li>
<li><p>introduction to Nmap code and scripting</p></li>
<li><p>the use of the GUI is not neglected</p></li>
<li><p>some dated content, but the updated information is available on the site</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, an excellent book that opened my eyes to the extent one can use Nmap for penetration testing..in fact, with all the scripts that are
available, you can even conduct web app security checks just with Nmap!</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nmap-Network-Scanning-Official-Discovery/dp/0979958717/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&linkCode=li2&tag=sensha10-20&linkId=791bdedacea7ac3bd1caea9852082708" target="_blank"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51BIsSMZqML._SX382_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg"/></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
