<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reviews | Core dump overflow]]></title>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-07-19T21:12:40+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://chousensha.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[chousensha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My review of Red Team Ops]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2020/07/19/my-review-of-red-team-ops/"/>
    <updated>2020-07-19T19:54:09+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2020/07/19/my-review-of-red-team-ops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Red Team Ops is a red team course launched by none other than RastaMouse. It was notoriously hard to get a free spot as the labs were full almost of the time since launch. I resorted to checking every day until I found a free seat to pounce on. Without a doubt, I can say it&rsquo;s been the best training experience I&rsquo;ve undertaken, and I wanted to leave a more in-depth review. You can find an overview of the course and its syllabus on the official page: <a href="https://www.zeropointsecurity.co.uk/red-team-ops">https://www.zeropointsecurity.co.uk/red-team-ops</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>RTO consists of the course materials, which are hosted on an online learning platform, and the labs, with users, servers, and a total of 3 domains. The materials are structured in such a way that you go more or less in order to complete the objectives. The explanations and examples are clear and concise, giving you enough for the task at hand. I liked the no fluff approach, and I also recognized that you can get a lot more out of the course if you research deeper into some topics to gain a better understanding of what&rsquo;s going on.</p>

<p>The course mirrors a red team engagement where the objective is not to pwn all the things but to compromise a target organization and exfiltrate important data. You start from the outside with minimal information and you have to go through recon, OSINT and phishing to get a foothold on the internal network. Then you get to use the taught techniques for privilege escalation, lateral movement, domain compromise and evading defenses, as well as maintaining persistence in the environment. Don&rsquo;t expect to use exploits on this course. Rather, you have to exploit typical Windows and Active Directory misconfigurations to accomplish your objectives. A lot of AD attacks are covered, as well as different tradecraft for various scenarios.</p>

<p>At the beginning the course used only Covenant as the C2 framework of choice, but with the continous updates now it also shows how to accomplish the objectives with Cobalt Strike. I learned a lot from using Covenant, even though at times its bugs drove me crazy. The course was initially created for Covenant 0.4, but since the 0.5 release, it got updates to reflect that. Covenant is really powerful for such a new framework, but at the same time is not as feature rich as older frameworks, so the course shows you ways to use other tools to augment the Covenant usage when necessary. In particular, I really learned a ton for using Metasploit for SOCKS proxies and reverse port forwards.</p>

<p>There is heavy emphasis on .NET tradecraft in the course, which is really nice considering that it&rsquo;s the current MO of choice for offensive operations. However, there is plenty of Powershell usage as well, so expect a well-rounded tradecraft experience. You don&rsquo;t just use tools all the time, sometimes you get to slightly modify code and compile tools and implants (called grunts in Covenant) to achieve the desired end state. All in all, the labs are spot on in terms of current tradecraft usage. There is a nice gamification effect as well. Throughout the labs you have to complete certain objectives by using specific attacks, so you can&rsquo;t skip content.</p>

<p>The exam is a beast on its own. You have 48 hours to collect 4 flags, and the passing score is 3 flags. You don&rsquo;t have to write a report. In the exam you will have to combine everything you learned and be really comfortable with the techniques and bypasses, ideally also how to achieve the same thing in different ways. It&rsquo;s a fun and difficult exam where you will switch from despair to joy and so on.</p>

<p>There are a couple other things that make an excellent course even greater, and that I haven&rsquo;t really seen with other courses, which I will list below.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Continuous updates</strong>. RastaMouse was true to his word that this course would receive regular updates. A number of sections were added, or more explanations and examples were added for specific sections, as well as rewriting the Covenant usage to reflect the changes from 0.4 to 0.5 and adding the Cobalt Strike examples to show how the same thing can be done with CS instead of Covenant.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Lifetime access</strong>. Combined with the above, it&rsquo;s really amazing. Once you buy the course, you get lifetime access to the materials, including the updates, so you can always go back and absorb the newly added material. You also have a different channel for buying lab extensions than the new purchases, with more custom lab time than the initial 1, 2, or 3 month duration.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fantastic support and community</strong>. The support offered in this course is exceptional. RastaMouse is super fast to help with any issues or to offer guidance on the dedicated Slack channel. And the channel is a perfect place to discuss with other students and learn from others, so it&rsquo;s definitely recommended to hang around!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Course format</strong>. There are 2 ways to get the Certified Red Team Operator certification. The external one is by having the OSCP and passing the RTO exam. The internal way, which I strongly recommend, is to achieve all the course objectives (you are granted a badge for each completed objective) and pass the RTO exam. The badge format is a nice motivator, as well as keeping your progress visualized and ensuring you don&rsquo;t skip tasks.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>As a conclusion, Red Team Ops was a fantasting learning experience for me and thanks to RastaMouse for creating it!</p>

<p>```</p>

<hr />

<p>&lt; Indeed. ></p>

<hr />

<pre><code>     \   ^__^ 
      \  (oo)\_______
         (__)\       )\/\
             ||----w |
             ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSCP flash review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2020/06/14/oscp-flash-review/"/>
    <updated>2020-06-14T20:07:43+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2020/06/14/oscp-flash-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve finished my OSCP shortly before <a href="https://www.offensive-security.com/pwk-oscp/">PWKv2</a> was released. Since my experience was pre-update, I didn&rsquo;t want to write a review that might no longer apply. Since then, I&rsquo;ve purchased the updated course materials, but I haven&rsquo;t yet gone back to do the newly added machines as well. I decided to write a quick review nonetheless, because I noticed a misconception about what the OSCP is. So I&rsquo;ll just address those points and not add just another OSCP review for the internet to swallow.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A quick rundown of my experience, I did all the lab machines and all the exam machines within 3 months. I plan to go back and also do the ones that were added by the update, but right now I am too busy with other things. After I do that, maybe I&rsquo;ll update this post or write a new one more focused on the impressions of the update. In terms of the new course materials, which I did review, there&rsquo;s a lot compared to the previous version. In particular, the new Windows section is superb and there are lots of usable snippets for various scenarios in modern environments.</p>

<p>Back to the reason for this post, it&rsquo;s not that I want to add just another post with what I did to prepare and the kind of information that is widely available already through the experiences of so many other successful takers (and you should read those posts and learn the most out of them to help you with your journey). My reason is that I noticed many people consider the OSCP the end all, be all of pentesting and are under the impression that it automatically makes you a pentesting god, while there are others who think it&rsquo;s overrated and that you don&rsquo;t learn much out of it. I consider both these opinion categories wrong. Let&rsquo;s dive in.</p>

<h3>My 50 cents about the OSCP</h3>

<p>After doing the OSCP and also moving beyond it, I consider it more like a necessary qualification to go through as a baseline for pentesting, much like the bootcamp in an army, training camp of a fight, or the qualifiers to a World Cup. It&rsquo;s hard and diverse enough, but it doesn&rsquo;t cover everything. It&rsquo;s mostly focused on network and web exploitation, along with enumeration and privilege escalation. Achieving it will demonstrate perseverance in front of obstacles, a working pentest methodology and skill, and a reasonable level of experience performing it. From that point, there&rsquo;s a lot on the horizon..going deeper in network and web attacks, exploit development, Active Directory..you realize when you&rsquo;re done that you just passed through a warpgate and now there&rsquo;s a whole lot of new challenges lining up. But the principles you learned through completing it will continue to be usable in your career and in future challenges.</p>

<h3>You get out what you put in</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve heard of several people who jumped into the exam after only going through a few machines in the labs. You are literally robbing yourself of the most valuable thing the OSCP provides. All the lab machines present a wide variety of operating systems (not just the usual flavors of Windows and Linux) and attack vectors. Some machines have different and unique vectors hidden in the attack surface that are way more rewarding than the obvious one. I don&rsquo;t think I used the same exploit more than 2 times in the lab. Each machine was a learning experience by itself. If you&rsquo;re running exploit suggester and throwing kernel exploits until one works, you&rsquo;re doing it wrong. Also, the hidden networks present a new challenge, in the way of pivoting, that needs to be solved before even reaching the targets. Not to mention the client side attacks and their difficulties.</p>

<p>Too many people are focusing just on the finality of earning a certification instead of squeezing the most out of all the labs have to offer. And even after you complete every box, don&rsquo;t imagine the exam won&rsquo;t be difficult. But you will be as prepared as you can get. Plus it&rsquo;s fun! If you don&rsquo;t get excited about the prospect of pwning over 50 boxes, why are you doing it in the first place? Your ROI will come from the effort you put into the labs, not from the letters you put on your resume.</p>

<h3>Outdated machines?</h3>

<p>Another thing I&rsquo;ve heard often is the complaint about lab machines being too outdated. Yes, the majority of boxes have older OS flavors..and that&rsquo;s a good thing! You can try your hand at exploits that will teach you things that you wouldn&rsquo;t otherwise experience in a completely modern environment. This is the foundation you are building, the training you&rsquo;re doing for match day. Plus, you learn to achieve objectives without your favorite tools. How do you transfer files to and from an older Windows machine without Powershell and all other native tools that you&rsquo;re used to? What can you do if you have RCE on a NIX system that&rsquo;s different than the ones you&rsquo;re familiar with? And many more wins that you arrive at from struggling with each challenge you&rsquo;re presented.</p>

<h3>Target audience</h3>

<p>Even with the new course update, which gives you a better starting point than before, I don&rsquo;t believe OSCP should be pursued for beginners. People who want to start in pentesting should first make sure they have their basics covered. Things like networking, system administration on Windows and Linux, programming, they are not basics as in easy and simple things, but as in the necessary foundation to add to with security. Trying to skip them won&rsquo;t end well. Once that is covered, there are lots of resources to prepare you, which I won&rsquo;t touch on here. VulnHub, HackTheBox, Ippsec, they have enough content to keep you busy for years. At some point, you have to dive in, but properly preparing for OSCP is as important an effort as working through it.</p>

<h3>Exam</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard and it&rsquo;s fun. Don&rsquo;t think just because you finished all the lab machines it will be a walk in the park &ndash; it won&rsquo;t ;). But I do believe that doing all the machines is the best way to gauge your readiness for it.</p>

<p>Keeping it short and to the point I intended, these are my thoughts about the OSCP. It&rsquo;s an awesome training experience and challenge. You constantly switch back and forth between frustration and elation. And once you&rsquo;re on the other side..you don&rsquo;t stop there, but you go forward exploring all that new fog of war.</p>

<p>```</p>

<hr />

<p>/ You definitely intend to start living \
\ sometime soon.                        /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>     \   ^__^ 
      \  (oo)\_______
         (__)\       )\/\
             ||----w |
             ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My OSWP review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/12/27/my-oswp-review/"/>
    <updated>2018-12-27T18:13:52+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/12/27/my-oswp-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to finish 2018 on a strong note, so right before Christmas I&rsquo;ve completed the exam for the <a href="https://www.offensive-security.com/information-security-certifications/oswp-offensive-security-wireless-professional/">Offensive Security Wireless Professional</a> (OSWP) certification. This is my review for the <a href="https://www.offensive-security.com/information-security-training/offensive-security-wireless-attacks/">Offensive Security Wireless Attacks (WiFu)</a> course. But as a short summay, the course and exam were great, very practical and applicable, and I thoroughly enjoyed them!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/oswp/oswp.png" title="&lsquo;oswp&rsquo; &lsquo;oswp&rsquo;" ></p>

<h2>The course</h2>

<p>The course consists of PDF material, videos, a BackTrack ISO and packet captures. The labs are hardware dependent, so you are supposed to procure your own hardware in order to practice the attacks. For my wireless card, I&rsquo;ve used Alfa AWUS036NHA and have been very happy with its performance. In the course, BackTrack is being used as the operating system, but I&rsquo;ve done the labs on Kali with minimal to none difference in commands.</p>

<p>As a testimony to the applicability of what you learn in the course, the author is none other than Thomas d'Otreppe de Bouvette, the creator of the Aircrack-NG suite! The material is very well structured and explained, you can practice what you&rsquo;re taught and see immediate results. Most chapters also contain a troubleshooting section with tips on what to try if you run into problems.</p>

<p>Almost half of the course written material revolves around the description of Wifi internals, how it works, how packets look like, hardware and drivers consideration. There are PCAP examples for what is being discussed, and it is really useful if you want to understand what is happening under the hood.</p>

<p>After that, it&rsquo;s all attacks and the stuff we&rsquo;re interested in! The focus of the course materials is the Aircrack-NG suite of tools, as expected, since it&rsquo;s the de facto choice for wireless security auditing. You learn how to place your wifi card on monitor mode, how to sniff traffic, how to do packet injection and ultimately crack the keys for different network scenarios. You also learn how to find hidden SSIDs and bypass MAC filtering.</p>

<p>The attacks you perform are targeted at different network types. There are multiple scenarios for WEP networks that use open authentication, shared key authentication, or have no associated clients. The labs go over multiple attacks: interactive packet replay attacks, fragmentation attacks, KoreK ChopChop attacks.</p>

<p>The most applicable part is the WPA/WPA2 cracking section, as these are the networks you&rsquo;ll run into most often nowadays. Dictionary and rainbow table attacks are being demonstrated with multiple tools. I&rsquo;ve really enjoyed the addition in the course material of Cowpatty and Pyrit. Also, you&rsquo;re shown how to leverage John&rsquo;s rules to enhance an already existing wordlist that&rsquo;s used with Aircrack-NG.</p>

<p>At the end of the course, you also get to see Kismet and Karmetasploit in action, along with rogue AP and man-in-the-middle attacks.</p>

<h2>The exam</h2>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/oswp/skills.png" title="&lsquo;oswp skills&rsquo; &lsquo;oswp skills&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The exam was really enjoyable, I didn&rsquo;t find it too hard or too easy. If you practice the labs in the course, you will be well prepared for the exam. I really liked that the exam takes almost 4 hours, as that allowed me to also work on the report as I was going through each attack. I&rsquo;ve experienced some laggy bits and a disconnection here and there, but overall, the exam experience was great.</p>

<h3>Concluding remarks</h3>

<p>I could think of no better course for wireless hacking, but as I was reading reviews of other people&rsquo;s experiences, I saw some criticism concerning this particular course. I will share my thoughts on the critiques below.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>The course is outdated</em>. It looks like the course was last updated in 2014, and the videos and labs make use of BackTrack. But these don&rsquo;t detract from its value at all. I used Kali for the course, and I think only 2 times I had to slightly alter the commands for use on Kali. It would make no sense to re-record everything just to be on Kali, since there are almost no differences between them. Also, the wifi landscape hasn&rsquo;t changed that much, so the material is highly relevant and you can put into practice what you learn right away. But I do agree that the course would be even better with a section of WPA enterprise attacks and WPS cracking.</p></li>
<li><p><em>The material is too WEP-centric</em>. It&rsquo;s true that today you won&rsquo;t really see WEP that much. But that&rsquo;s not to say that there are no WEP networks left in the world. Seeing how vulnerable they are in reality and being able to crack different types of WEP networks is a skill that you should have, regardless of how rare you&rsquo;ll get to see them. So for me, this wasn&rsquo;t a weak point at all, I found it very interesting.</p></li>
<li><p><em>The exam is too easy</em>. I&rsquo;ve also seen several opinions claiming that the exam was too easy. But this only attests to the quality of the material, if you can perform the attacks you&rsquo;re being taught, you will succeed. Maybe as an enhancement to the exam, besides cracking the keys, there could be some objectives like decrypting the traffic of a certain client to discover something, or performing MitM. But I was happy with the quality of the exam, in fact, I tried to make the most of it by going through the attacks with more than one tool.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All in all, OSWP was awesome, and stay tuned for more!</p>

<p>```</p>

<hr />

<p>/ Living your life is a task so          \
| difficult, it has never been attempted |
\ before.                                /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social Engineering Expert course review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/11/11/social-engineering-expert-course-review/"/>
    <updated>2018-11-11T13:17:57+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2018/11/11/social-engineering-expert-course-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently taken the <a href="https://redteam-training.thinkific.com/courses/social-engineering-expert">Social Engineering Expert</a> from <a href="https://www.redteamsecure.com/">RedTeam Security</a>. If you don&rsquo;t know about them, check out their articles and videos about their engagements, they&rsquo;re doing some really cool stuff. In this post I will share my impressions about the course.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all, the author of the course is also the founder of RedTeam Security, Jeremiah Talamantes. He&rsquo;s authored a book called <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Social-Engineers-Playbook-Practical-Pretexting/dp/0692306617/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1452290969&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=social+engineers+playbook&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=talamantesus-20&amp;linkId=1f8b9cac92cdd16ae8d1956668d9942b">The Social Engineer’s Playbook: A Practical Guide to Pretexting</a>
, which I haven&rsquo;t tried yet. He is clearly very experienced and throughout the course, he&rsquo;s sharing various stories from the operations he&rsquo;s conducted.</p>

<p>The course is priced at 59$, but there are discounts every now and then. The training is video-based, where the instructor is sharing slides and talking about the topics. There are some valuable documents that can be downloaded, mainly templates and sample models for social engineering reports, plans and field notes guides. These can be used as starting points for your own operations.</p>

<p>As for the main structure of the course, it is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Introduction to social engineering</strong> &ndash; this covers the terminology around SE (it&rsquo;s getting tiring to type that) and goes through several examples</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Attack vectors</strong> &ndash; very useful section for actually conducting a SE campaign, it goes over different techniques and tools for social engineering your target, with actionable tips that you can use right away to enhance your operations. It also summarizes an attack in a very clear way, through the Social Engineering Kill Chain</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Methodology</strong> &ndash; this is another very practical section that covers planning and execution.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Information gathering</strong> &ndash; physical and digital techniques for information gathering. There is a gear list for physical reconaissance that makes for a good reference. However, I found the digital side to be under-represented, only Maltego and Metagoofill are discussed. I would have expected at least a breakdown of the SET functionality, and more demos about OSINT and conducting phishing campaigns.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Psychology &amp; manipulation</strong> &ndash; very applicable in day-to-day life, not limited to the field of security and SE, this describes various influencing and elicitation techniques that can be used to gain information or an expected behavior from a target. Not only that, but it also gives you awareness of such techniques being used on you.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Non-verbal communicaton</strong> &ndash; this is where micro expressions and body language are discussed. It essentially gives you a roadmap for reading people&rsquo;s true feelings and intentions, detecting lies, and masking your own thoughts. Very practical to be aware of these thing in all kinds of settings and social interactions.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>All in all, I&rsquo;ve really enjoyed this course and highly recommend it. What would have made it even better would have been a practical component in order to complete it, a lab or task around phishing / OSINT, especially since at the end you get a certification. That being said, this is a very solid course and you don&rsquo;t need to be social engineered to get it :D</p>

<p>```</p>

<hr />

<p>/ Change your thoughts and you change \
\ your world.                         /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CCNA Cyber Ops review]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/ccna-cyber-ops-review/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-09T10:11:41+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/ccna-cyber-ops-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cisco Cybersecurity Scholarship program has concluded for the first cohort, and I have been fortunate enough to make it into the program! Now that the course and 2 exams are over, and I have a brand new certification, I thought I&rsquo;d share some info about what is covered in the CCNA Cyber Ops study materials.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, I&rsquo;d like to thank Cisco for this amazing opportunity, and I wish more vendors would take their example. Yes, the latest exam price increase isn&rsquo;t nice, but this offering of a new certification&rsquo;s courses and exams to 10 000 people was an awesome move, especially for people who shared an interest in the security topics but wouldn&rsquo;t have gone to the certification path due to costs.</p>

<p>It also helped in bringing like-minded people together, creating communities and study groups over social media networks, and exchanging information about various security subjects.</p>

<p>So, what is this new CCNA that has the word &ldquo;cyber&rdquo; in it all about?</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/cyber.JPG" title="&lsquo;ccna cyber&rsquo; &lsquo;ccna cyber ops&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The certification aims to prepare people for working as security analysts in a Security Operations Center. This is a blue-team focused certification, and here are the skills that it covers:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/study/skills.JPG" title="&lsquo;ccna cyber skills&rsquo; &lsquo;ccna cyber ops skills&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The scholarship consisted of 3 courses that had to be completed within 3 months, free vouchers for the 2 exams, and access to forums and mentors.</p>

<p><strong>Introduction to cybersecurity</strong></p>

<p>The first course was a very basic introductory course on what cybersecurity is and why it is needed. You can take it for free from Cisco&rsquo;s Networking Academy. This was a prerequisite for starting the other 2 courses that actually made up the certification part.</p>

<p><strong>Understanding Cisco cybersecurity fundamentals</strong></p>

<p>This second course was a blast! 14 sections, massive amount of material, both writen and videos, lots of information covered, I really enjoyed it! Some of it was review for me, but I also learned plenty of new things about DHCP relays, the CAPWAP protocol, the Security Onion suite, which is like the Kali of defensive security, and much more! The cryptograhpy section was excellently explained, and the Linux chapter might as well be a course in itself. Here&rsquo;s a list with some of the topics:</p>

<ul>
<li>networking stuff, protocols, attacks, devices</li>
<li>cryptography &ndash; detailed and easy to understand</li>
<li>general infosec concepts</li>
<li>web attacks</li>
<li>Windows and Linux sections with commands, filesystem structure, the ways the OS works, etc.</li>
<li>network and host security</li>
<li>various types of security devices and logs</li>
<li>different types of models that deal with threats</li>
</ul>


<p>A great addition to the study materials were the labs, where you could play with various OSes and tools in your browser, simulate attacks and react to different scenarios. It took a while for the labs to be initialized, but there were also walkthroughs for doing the lab, or skipping it altogether and following the steps instead.</p>

<p>You can find the exam topics for this course at <a href="https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secfnd/exam-topics">https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secfnd/exam-topics</a></p>

<p><strong>Implementing Cisco cybersecurity operations</strong></p>

<p>This course wasn&rsquo;t as big as the previous one, it had 13 sections and 2 appendices. It built up on the foundation of the other one, focusing on various aspects of incident response. It felt a bit rushed though, as it could have covered more material instead of breezing through, and the amount of typos that I found in it was pretty high. But overall, it was a good follow-up, and it had links for many resources where you could learn more. Some of the topics covered are:</p>

<ul>
<li>types of SOCs, NSM tools and data</li>
<li>incident analysis and threat hunting</li>
<li>CVSS scoring</li>
<li>data manipulation, correlation and normalization</li>
<li>incident detection and playbooks</li>
<li>incident response and automation</li>
</ul>


<p>The biggest problem that I faced before the exam was that the exam topics didn&rsquo;t follow the course content. Here is the exam guide: <a href="https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secops/exam-topics">https://learningnetwork.cisco.com/community/certifications/ccna-cyber-ops/secops/exam-topics</a></p>

<p>Fortunately, the mentors assigned to us were very helpful, and in addition to hosting webinars that reinforced the study material, they put together some documents that followed the exam blueprint and filled the gaps in information.</p>

<p>Overall, this has been a very interesting experience and I am happy to have participated in it! Again, hats off to Cisco for making this program available to security enthusiasts, and happy threat hunting!</p>

<p>``` plain</p>

<hr />

<p>/ You worry too much about your job. Stop \
\ it. You are not paid enough to worry.   /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
