<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | Core dump overflow]]></title>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-10T07:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chousensha.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[chousensha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloning Octopress blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2015/11/26/cloning-octopress-blog/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-26T11:16:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2015/11/26/cloning-octopress-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently had some problems with Octopress breaking on my old Kali 1.0 box. And since the Kali 1.0 reached its end of life, figured this might be a good time to jump ship and install the 2.0 version, and set up a fresh Octopress there. So in this post I will quickly overview the steps needed to clone an already existing Octopress blog on a new machine and resume blogging from there.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h4>clone the source branch repository</h4>

<p>git clone -b source <a href="https://github.com/chousensha/chousensha.github.io.git">https://github.com/chousensha/chousensha.github.io.git</a> octopress</p>

<p>cd octopress</p>

<h4>clone master branch to _deploy</h4>

<p>git clone <a href="https://github.com/chousensha/chousensha.github.io.git">https://github.com/chousensha/chousensha.github.io.git</a> _deploy</p>

<p>The <code>source</code> branch contains the source of your blog, while the content that you generate is in the <code>master</code> branch.</p>

<p>Before proceeding with installing dependencies, I followed the instructions on <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">http://octopress.org/docs/setup/</a> to install rvm, Ruby 1.9.3 and ExecJs:</p>

<h4>install rvm</h4>

<p>command curl -sSL <a href="https://rvm.io/mpapis.asc">https://rvm.io/mpapis.asc</a> | gpg2 &mdash;import &ndash;
curl -L <a href="https://get.rvm.io">https://get.rvm.io</a> | bash -s stable &mdash;ruby</p>

<h4>run below to be able to use rvm in the shell windows, and add it to your shell rc file or you will need to always run it before using rvm</h4>

<p>source /usr/local/rvm/scripts/rvm</p>

<h4>install Ruby 1.9.3</h4>

<p>rvm install 1.9.3</p>

<p>You will get a message that this version of Ruby is no longer maintained, but I had problems with Ruby 2~ so keeping this for Octopress.</p>

<h4>use Ruby 1.9.3</h4>

<p>rvm use 1.9.3</p>

<h4>update the rubygems to the latest available</h4>

<p>rvm rubygems latest</p>

<h4>optional: check that your Ruby version is the right one</h4>

<p>ruby &mdash;version</p>

<h4>install JS runtime for Ruby</h4>

<p>gem install execjs</p>

<h4>now install dependencies</h4>

<p>gem install bundler
bundle install</p>

<h4>setup github pages</h4>

<p>bundle exec rake setup_github_pages</p>

<p>And you&rsquo;re good to go!</p>

<p>Note for <em>zsh</em> users: because of the globbing of <em>zsh</em>, you will need to add <code>alias rake=&ldquo;noglob rake&rdquo;</code> to your .zshrc file or you will get a no matches found error. Or you can quote the arguments given to rake: <code>rake &ldquo;new_post[Whatever]&rdquo;</code></p>

<p>``` plain</p>

<hr />

<p>/ Few things are harder to put up with  \
| than the annoyance of a good example. |
|                                       |
| &mdash; &ldquo;Mark Twain, Pudd'nhead Wilson&rsquo;s   |
\ Calendar&rdquo;                             /</p>

<hr />

<pre><code>    \   ^__^
     \  (oo)\_______
        (__)\       )\/\
            ||----w |
            ||     ||
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/setting-up-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T14:44:43-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/setting-up-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I now got the blog up and running, I want to walk through the steps of setting it up and where I had to do some extra work not mentioned in the official documentation, which by the way, is a good place to start reading about Octopress.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, I want to mention that starting an Octopress blog is not a daunting task at all. You don&rsquo;t need to know Ruby, the main commands for getting it to work are already implemented for you. The files you need to modify are intuitive and structured in a logical way, and the <code>markdown</code> language is easy to use even if you never heard of it before ( I certainly hadn&rsquo;t before starting with Octopress ). Some basic familiarity with a command shell and Git is all that&rsquo;s really needed! So if you want the awesome looks and other perks of Octopress, it&rsquo;s not hard at all to get them!</p>

<p>So, Octopress is built on top of Jekyll, which is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator based on Ruby. Jekyll is actually the engine behind GitHub Pages. Being static, it&rsquo;s very fast and no myriad features that you don&rsquo;t really need are cluttering up the server side. And Octopress gives you the necessary tools to customize and maintain a blog in a flexible and convenient way. It also comes loaded with plugins for many 3rd party services that you might want to use.</p>

<h3>Installation</h3>

<p>You need to have Git and Ruby 1.9.3 or greater before installing Octopress. You can check your Ruby version with this command: <code>ruby &mdash;version</code></p>

<p>To start with, clone the Octopress repository and give it the name you want:</p>

<p><code>plain
git clone git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git blogname
</code></p>

<p>Then, install dependencies. I had to install the <code>ruby1.9.1-dev</code> package before the <em>bundle install</em> would work.</p>

<p><code>plain
gem install bundler
bundle install
</code></p>

<p>Next, install the default Octopress theme:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake install
</code></p>

<h3>Configuration</h3>

<p>To configure your blog, you need to edit the <code>_config.yml</code> file. There you can add your blog URL, description categories, 3rd party integration, and other stuff.</p>

<h3>Content</h3>

<p>To create a post, you run the following rake task:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake new_post["title"]
</code></p>

<p>This will create a <code>markdown</code> post in the <code>source/_posts</code> directory. Use your favorite text editor to edit it and add your post body. Markdown is really easy to use, just look at one of reference sheets available on the web to get started with it.</p>

<p>Similarly, if you want to create a new page, you do it like this:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake new_page[page]
</code></p>

<p>To see how your posts look:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake preview
</code></p>

<p>This will start a small server on port 4000 that will let you view your pages on your local machine. Check it out in your browser by navigating to <code><a href="http://localhost:4000/">http://localhost:4000/</a></code></p>

<h3>Deployment</h3>

<p>To generate your blog (populate the public directory with your posts and pages) run:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake generate
</code></p>

<p>Now you are ready to deploy it. I use Github Pages for the blog. If you want it hosted on Github, there&rsquo;s a rake task available for it, but first you need to create a new repository that should look like this: <code>username.github.io</code></p>

<p>Then run:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake setup_github_pages
</code></p>

<p>You will be asked for the URL of your newly created repository, which you can copy from the HTTPS or SSH URL available on its page.</p>

<p>After that&rsquo;s done, you can deploy your generated files with:</p>

<p><code>plain
rake deploy
</code></p>

<p>This will commit your files and push them to the master branch. You will want to commit your sorce, too. In your blog directory, run these git commands:</p>

<p><code>plain
git add .
git commit -m 'message here'
git push origin source
</code></p>

<p>And now you have an awesome Octopress blog out there on the web!</p>

<h4>Disqus comments</h4>

<p>To enable comments, in your _config.yml file, look for these lines and change them accordingly:</p>

<p><code>plain
disqus_short_name: your-disqus-shortname # your website shortname on disqus
disqus_show_comment_count: true
</code></p>

<p>When setting up your site on Disqus, be careful with the URL you give it. Pass it like this:</p>

<p><em>mysite.com</em></p>

<p>instead of this:</p>

<p><em>mysite.com/</em></p>

<p>Because Disqus adds a trailing slash after your URL, if you also provide one, you will end up with 2 slashes and Disqus won&rsquo;t work.</p>

<h3>SEO</h3>

<h4>Google Analytics</h4>

<p>To get Google Analytics to track your blog, all you need to do is add your tracking id in the <code>_config.yml</code> file:</p>

<p>``` plain</p>

<h1>Google Analytics</h1>

<p>google_analytics_tracking_id: your id
```</p>

<h4>Meta tags and description</h4>

<p>To add keywords and description for each individual post, you have to manually add them to every post (before the dashed line):</p>

<p><code>plain
keywords: keyword 1, keyword 2
description: Description for the post
</code></p>

<p>And to add keywords and description for the blog as a whole (by default, Octopress uses the ones from your latest post), edit your <code>_config.yml</code> file (I only had to add the keywords tag, description was already there):</p>

<p><code>plain
decription: Your blog description
keywords: keyword 1, keyword 2
</code></p>

<p>Now you need to make one final modification to generate the meta tags in your HTML. Go to your <code>source/_includes/head.html</code> file.</p>

<p>Under the <em>author</em> meta tag, replace this line:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/replaceme.png" title="&lsquo;replace this&rsquo; &lsquo;line to replace&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>with this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/replacewith.png" title="&lsquo;replace with&rsquo; &lsquo;replace with this&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>And that&rsquo;s pretty much what I had to do for this blog!</p>

<p>Not forgetting the cookie:</p>

<blockquote><p>You will give someone a piece of your mind, which you can ill afford.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
