<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kali | Core dump overflow]]></title>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/categories/kali/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-20T00:54:00+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://chousensha.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[chousensha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kali tools catalog - Vulnerability Analysis]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/09/17/kali-tools-catalog-vulnerability-analysis/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-17T21:36:25+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/09/17/kali-tools-catalog-vulnerability-analysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I am going to continue with cataloguing the security tools that are installed on Kali. Next is the Vulnerability Analysis section.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Cisco Tools</h3>

<p><strong>cisco-global-exploiter</strong></p>

<p>Cisco Global Exploiter (CGE), is an advanced, simple and fast security testing tool/ exploit engine, that is able to exploit 14 vulnerabilities in disparate Cisco switches and routers.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/cge.png" title="&lsquo;cge&rsquo; &lsquo;cge&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>cisco-ocs</strong></p>

<p>Compact mass scanner for Cisco routers with default telnet/enable passwords.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/cisco-ocs.png" title="&lsquo;cisco-ocs&rsquo; &lsquo;cisco-ocs&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>yersinia</strong></p>

<p>yersinia is a framework for performing layer 2 attacks. The following protocols have
been implemented in Yersinia current version: Spanning  Tree  Protocol  (STP),  VLAN
Trunking Protocol (VTP), Hot Standby Router Protocol (HSRP), Dynamic Trunking Protocol (DTP), IEEE 802.1Q, IEEE 802.1X, Cisco Discovery Protocol  (CDP),  Dynamic  Host
Configuration  Protocol  (DHCP),  Inter-Switch Link Protocol (ISL) and MultiProtocol Label Switching (MPLS).</p>

<p>Some of the attacks implemented will cause a DoS in a network, other  will  help  to
perform  any  other more advanced attack, or both. In addition, some of them will be
first released to the public since there isn&rsquo;t any public implementation.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/yersinia.png" title="&lsquo;yersinia&rsquo; &lsquo;yersinia&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Database Assessment</h3>

<p><strong>bbqsql</strong></p>

<p>BBQSQL is a blind SQL injection framework written in Python.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/bbqsql.png" title="&lsquo;bbqsql&rsquo; &lsquo;bbqsql&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dbpwaudit</strong></p>

<p>DBPwAudit is a Java tool that allows you to perform online audits of password quality for several database engines.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/dbpwaudit.png" title="&lsquo;dbpwaudit&rsquo; &lsquo;dbpwaudit&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>hexorbase</strong></p>

<p>HexorBase is a database application designed for administering and auditing multiple database servers simultaneously from a centralized location, it is capable of performing SQL queries and bruteforce attacks against common database servers (MySQL, SQLite, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL ).HexorBase allows packet routing through proxies or even metasploit pivoting antics to communicate with remotely inaccessible servers which are hidden within local subnets.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/hexorbase.png" title="&lsquo;hexorbase&rsquo; &lsquo;hexorbase&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>jsql</strong></p>

<p>jSQL Injection is a lightweight application used to find database information from a distant server.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/jsql.png" title="&lsquo;jsql&rsquo; &lsquo;jsql&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>mdb-export</strong></p>

<p>Export data in an MDB database table to CSV format.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/mdb-export.png" title="&lsquo;mdb-export&rsquo; &lsquo;mdb-export&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>mdb-hexdump</strong></p>

<p>makes a hex dump of a binary file</p>

<p><strong>mdb-parsecsv</strong></p>

<p>mdb-parsecsv  takes  a CSV file representing a database table, and converts it into a C array.</p>

<p><strong>mdb-sql</strong></p>

<p>mdb-sql  allows  querying of an MDB database using a limited SQL subset language.</p>

<p><strong>mdb-tables</strong></p>

<p>It produces a list of tables contained within an MDB database in a format suitable for use in shell scripts.</p>

<p><strong>oscanner</strong></p>

<p>Oscanner is an Oracle assessment framework developed in Java. It has a plugin-based architecture and comes with a couple of plugins that currently do:</p>

<p>– Sid Enumeration
– Passwords tests (common &amp; dictionary)
– Enumerate Oracle version
– Enumerate account roles
– Enumerate account privileges
– Enumerate account hashes
– Enumerate audit information
– Enumerate password policies
– Enumerate database links</p>

<p>The results are given in a graphical java tree.</p>

<p><strong>sidguesser</strong></p>

<p>Guesses sids/instances against an Oracle database according to a predefined dictionary file.</p>

<p><strong>sqldict</strong></p>

<p>SQLdict is a basic single ip brute-force MS SQL Server password utility that can carry out a dictionary attack against a named SQL account.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/sqldict.png" title="&lsquo;sqldict&rsquo; &lsquo;sqldict&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sqlmap</strong></p>

<p>sqlmap  is  an automatic SQL injection tool entirely developed in Python.  Its goal is to detect and take advantage of SQL injection vulnerabilities on web applications. Once it
detects one or more SQL injections on the target host, the user can choose among a variety of options to perform an extensive back-end database  management  system  fingerprint,
retrieve  DBMS  session  user  and  database, enumerate users, password hashes, privileges, databases, dump entire or user&rsquo;s specific DBMS tables/columns, run his own SQL SELECT
statement, read specific files on the file system and much more.</p>

<p>``` plain
Usage: python sqlmap [options]</p>

<p>Options:
  -h, &mdash;help            Show basic help message and exit
  -hh                   Show advanced help message and exit
  &mdash;version             Show program&rsquo;s version number and exit
  -v VERBOSE            Verbosity level: 0-6 (default 1)</p>

<p>  Target:</p>

<pre><code>At least one of these options has to be provided to define the
target(s)

-u URL, --url=URL   Target URL (e.g. "http://www.site.com/vuln.php?id=1")
-g GOOGLEDORK       Process Google dork results as target URLs
</code></pre>

<p>  Request:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to specify how to connect to the target URL

--data=DATA         Data string to be sent through POST
--cookie=COOKIE     HTTP Cookie header value
--random-agent      Use randomly selected HTTP User-Agent header value
--proxy=PROXY       Use a proxy to connect to the target URL
--tor               Use Tor anonymity network
--check-tor         Check to see if Tor is used properly
</code></pre>

<p>  Injection:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to specify which parameters to test for,
provide custom injection payloads and optional tampering scripts

-p TESTPARAMETER    Testable parameter(s)
--dbms=DBMS         Force back-end DBMS to this value
</code></pre>

<p>  Detection:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to customize the detection phase

--level=LEVEL       Level of tests to perform (1-5, default 1)
--risk=RISK         Risk of tests to perform (0-3, default 1)
</code></pre>

<p>  Techniques:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to tweak testing of specific SQL injection
techniques

--technique=TECH    SQL injection techniques to use (default "BEUSTQ")
</code></pre>

<p>  Enumeration:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to enumerate the back-end database
management system information, structure and data contained in the
tables. Moreover you can run your own SQL statements

-a, --all           Retrieve everything
-b, --banner        Retrieve DBMS banner
--current-user      Retrieve DBMS current user
--current-db        Retrieve DBMS current database
--passwords         Enumerate DBMS users password hashes
--tables            Enumerate DBMS database tables
--columns           Enumerate DBMS database table columns
--schema            Enumerate DBMS schema
--dump              Dump DBMS database table entries
--dump-all          Dump all DBMS databases tables entries
-D DB               DBMS database to enumerate
-T TBL              DBMS database table(s) to enumerate
-C COL              DBMS database table column(s) to enumerate
</code></pre>

<p>  Operating system access:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to access the back-end database management
system underlying operating system

--os-shell          Prompt for an interactive operating system shell
--os-pwn            Prompt for an OOB shell, Meterpreter or VNC
</code></pre>

<p>  General:</p>

<pre><code>These options can be used to set some general working parameters

--batch             Never ask for user input, use the default behaviour
--flush-session     Flush session files for current target
</code></pre>

<p>  Miscellaneous:</p>

<pre><code>--sqlmap-shell      Prompt for an interactive sqlmap shell
--wizard            Simple wizard interface for beginner users
</code></pre>

<p>[!] to see full list of options run with &lsquo;-hh&rsquo;
```</p>

<p><strong>sqlninja</strong></p>

<p>Sqlninja is a tool targeted to exploit SQL Injection vulnerabilities on a web application that uses Microsoft SQL Server as its back-end.</p>

<p>Features:</p>

<p>Fingerprint of the remote SQL Server (version, user performing the queries, user privileges, xp_cmdshell availability, DB authentication mode)</p>

<p>Data extraction, time-based or via a DNS tunnel</p>

<p>Integration with Metasploit3, to obtain a graphical access to the remote DB server through a VNC server injection or just to upload Meterpreter</p>

<p>Upload of executables using only normal HTTP requests (no FTP/TFTP needed), via vbscript or debug.exe</p>

<p>Direct and reverse bindshell, both TCP and UDP</p>

<p>DNS-tunneled pseudo-shell, when no TCP/UDP ports are available for a direct/reverse shell, but the DB server can resolve external hostnames</p>

<p>ICMP-tunneled shell, when no TCP/UDP ports are available for a direct/reverse shell but the DB can ping your box</p>

<p>Bruteforce of &lsquo;sa&rsquo; password (in 2 flavors: dictionary-based and incremental)</p>

<p>Privilege escalation to sysadmin group if &lsquo;sa&rsquo; password has been found</p>

<p>Creation of a custom xp_cmdshell if the original one has been removed</p>

<p>TCP/UDP portscan from the target SQL Server to the attacking machine, in order to find a port that is allowed by the firewall of the target network and use it for a reverse shell</p>

<p>Evasion techniques to confuse a few IDS/IPS/WAF</p>

<p>Integration with churrasco.exe, to escalate privileges to SYSTEM on w2k3 via token kidnapping</p>

<p>Support for CVE-2010-0232, to escalate the privileges of sqlservr.exe to SYSTEM</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/sqlninja.png" title="&lsquo;sqlninja&rsquo; &lsquo;sqlninja&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sqlsus</strong></p>

<p>sqlsus is an open source MySQL injection and takeover tool, written in perl.</p>

<p><strong>tnscmd10g</strong></p>

<p>Tnscmd can be used to communicate directly with Oracle&rsquo;s TNS listener, (no client is needed).  Unlike the Oracle
listener control utility LSNRCTL.exe, TNSCmd.pl does not need any connection strings and a direct
bi-directional conversation can be immediately established.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/tnscmd10g.png" title="&lsquo;tnscmd10g&rsquo; &lsquo;tnscmd10g&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Fuzzing Tools</h3>

<p><strong>bed</strong></p>

<p>Bruteforce Exploit Detector is a plain-text protocol fuzzer that checks software for common vulnerabilities like buffer overflows, format string bugs, integer overflows, etc.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/bed.png" title="&lsquo;bed&rsquo; &lsquo;bed&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>fuzz_ip6</strong></p>

<p>The name is self explanatory.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/fuzz_ip6.png" title="&lsquo;fuzz_ip6&rsquo; &lsquo;fuzz_ip6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>ohrwurm</strong></p>

<p>RTP fuzzer</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/ohrwurm.png" title="&lsquo;ohrwurm&rsquo; &lsquo;ohrwurm&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>powerfuzzer</strong></p>

<p>highly automated and fully customizable web fuzzer (HTTP protocol based application fuzzer)</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/powerfuzzer.png" title="&lsquo;powerfuzzer&rsquo; &lsquo;powerfuzzer&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sfuzz</strong></p>

<p>Simple Fuzz(sfuzz) is a simple fuzzer. It has two network modes of operation, an output mode for developing command line fuzzing scripts, as well as taking fuzzing strings from literals and building strings from sequences.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/sfuzz.png" title="&lsquo;sfuzz&rsquo; &lsquo;sfuzz&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>siparmyknife</strong></p>

<p>SIP Army Knife is a fuzzer that searches for cross site scripting, SQL injection, log injection, format strings, buffer overflows, and more.</p>

<p><strong>spike generic_chunked &amp; generic_listen_tcp &amp; generic_send_tcp &amp; generic_send_udp</strong></p>

<p>SPIKE is a Fuzzer Creation Kit. You can use it for fuzzing or leverage its API to write your own fuzzers.</p>

<h3>Misc Scanners</h3>

<p><strong>golismero</strong></p>

<p>GoLismero is an open source framework for security testing. It&rsquo;s currently geared towards web security, but it can easily be expanded to other kinds of scans.</p>

<p>``` plain
/&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;\
| GoLismero 2.0.0b3 &ndash; The Web Knife            |
| Contact: golismero.project&lt;@>gmail.com       |
|                                              |
| Daniel Garcia Garcia a.k.a cr0hn (@ggdaniel) |
| Mario Vilas (@Mario_Vilas)                   |
-&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&mdash;&ndash;/</p>

<p>usage: golismero.py COMMAND [TARGETS&hellip;] [&mdash;options]</p>

<p>  SCAN:</p>

<pre><code>Perform a vulnerability scan on the given targets. Optionally import
results from other tools and write a report. The arguments that follow may
be domain names, IP addresses or web pages.
</code></pre>

<p>  PROFILES:</p>

<pre><code>Show a list of available config profiles. This command takes no arguments.
</code></pre>

<p>  PLUGINS:</p>

<pre><code>Show a list of available plugins. This command takes no arguments.
</code></pre>

<p>  INFO:</p>

<pre><code>Show detailed information on a given plugin. The arguments that follow are
the plugin IDs. You can use glob-style wildcards.
</code></pre>

<p>  REPORT:</p>

<pre><code>Write a report from an earlier scan. This command takes no arguments.
To specify output files use the -o switch.
</code></pre>

<p>  IMPORT:</p>

<pre><code>Import results from other tools and optionally write a report, but don't
scan the targets. This command takes no arguments. To specify input files
use the -i switch.
</code></pre>

<p>  DUMP:</p>

<pre><code>Dump the database from an earlier scan in SQL format. This command takes no
arguments. To specify output files use the -o switch.
</code></pre>

<p>  UPDATE:</p>

<pre><code>Update GoLismero to the latest version. Requires Git to be installed and
available in the PATH. This command takes no arguments.
</code></pre>

<p>examples:</p>

<p>  scan a website and show the results on screen:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py scan http://www.example.com
</code></pre>

<p>  grab Nmap results, scan all hosts found and write an HTML report:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py scan -i nmap_output.xml -o report.html
</code></pre>

<p>  grab results from OpenVAS and show them on screen, but don&rsquo;t scan anything:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py import -i openvas_output.xml
</code></pre>

<p>  show a list of all available configuration profiles:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py profiles
</code></pre>

<p>  show a list of all available plugins:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py plugins
</code></pre>

<p>  show information on all bruteforcer plugins:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py info brute_*
</code></pre>

<p>  dump the database from a previous scan:</p>

<pre><code>golismero.py dump -db example.db -o dump.sql
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p><strong>lynis</strong></p>

<p>Run a system and security audit on the system</p>

<p>The following system areas may be checked:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Boot loader files</p></li>
<li><p>Configuration files</p></li>
<li><p>Common files by software packages</p></li>
<li><p>Directories and files related to logging and auditing</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/lynis.png" title="&lsquo;lynis&rsquo; &lsquo;lynis&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>nikto</strong></p>

<p>Examine a web server to find potential problems and security vulnerabilities, including:</p>

<p>·   Server and software misconfigurations</p>

<p>·   Default files and programs</p>

<p>·   Insecure files and programs</p>

<p>·   Outdated servers and programs</p>

<p>Nikto is built on LibWhisker (by RFP) and can run on any platform which has a Perl
environment. It supports SSL, proxies, host authentication, IDS evasion and more. It
can be updated automatically from the command-line, and supports the optional
submission of updated version data back to the maintainers.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/nikto.png" title="&lsquo;nikto&rsquo; &lsquo;nikto&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>unix-privesc-check</strong></p>

<p>This script checks file permissions and other settings that could allow local users to escalate privileges.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/unix-privesc-check.png" title="&lsquo;unix-privesc-check&rsquo; &lsquo;unix-privesc-check&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Open Source Assessment</h3>

<p>Covered in other categories.</p>

<h3>OpenVAS</h3>

<p>OpenVAS is a framework of several services and tools offering a comprehensive and powerful vulnerability scanning and vulnerability management solution.</p>

<p><strong>openvas-check-setup</strong></p>

<p>analyzes the state of your OpenVAS installation and proposes fixes should it detect any errors or misconfigurations. It will also check if all required OpenVAS services are running and listening on the correct ports.</p>

<p><strong>openvas-gsd</strong></p>

<p>The Greenbone Security Desktop (GSD) is a Qt-based desktop client for the OpenVAS Management Protocol</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/vuln/openvas.png" title="&lsquo;openvas&rsquo; &lsquo;openvas&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s see what fortune has in store for today:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t look now, but there is a multi-legged creature on your shoulder.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kali tools catalog - Information Gathering]]></title>
    <link href="http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/kali-tools-catalog-information-gathering/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T21:25:37+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://chousensha.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/kali-tools-catalog-information-gathering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kali is an awesome distribution for pentesting. But with so many choices, one may find it daunting to find a specific tool for a task without having used it before. Or maybe you&rsquo;re wondering about some tools but don&rsquo;t feel like testing every single one. So I decided to briefly go over the tools provided by Kali and provide a quick description. Where available, I will use the ones presented on their respective websites / manpages etc.</p>

<p>So, let&rsquo;s begin!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>DNS Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>dnsdict6</strong></p>

<p>Enumerates a domain for DNS entries, it uses a dictionary file if supplied or a built-in list otherwise. This tool is based on dnsmap by gnucitizen.org.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dnsdict6.png" title="&lsquo;dnsdict6&rsquo; &lsquo;dnsdict6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnsenum</strong></p>

<p>Multithreaded perl script to enumerate DNS information of a domain and to discover non-contiguous ip blocks.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dnsenum.png" title="&lsquo;dnsenum&rsquo; &lsquo;dnsenum&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnsmap</strong></p>

<p>dnsmap is mainly meant to be used by pentesters during the informatio ngathering/enumeration phase of infrastructure security assessments. During the enumeration stage, the security consultant would typically discover the target company&rsquo;s IP netblocks, domain names, phone numbers, etc &hellip;</p>

<p>Subdomain brute-forcing is another technique that should be used in the enumeration stage, as it&rsquo;s especially useful when other domain enumeration techniques such as zone transfers don&rsquo;t work (I rarely see zone transfers being <em>publicly</em> allowed these days by the way).</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dnsmap.png" title="&lsquo;dnsmap&rsquo; &lsquo;dnsmap&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnsrecon</strong></p>

<p>DNS Enumueration and Scanning Tool</p>

<p>The script will perform the following:</p>

<p>Standard  Record  Enumeration for a given domain (A, NS, SOA and MX).</p>

<p>Top Leven Domain Expansion for a given domain.</p>

<p>Zone Transfer against all  NS records of a given domain.</p>

<p>Reverse Lookup against a given IP Range given a start and end IP.</p>

<p>SRV Record enumeration</p>

<p>Brute force hostnames and subdomains of a given target domain  using  a wordlist.</p>

<p>``` plain
Version: 0.8.8
Usage: dnsrecon.py <options></p>

<p>Options:
   -h, &mdash;help                  Show this help message and exit
   -d, &mdash;domain      <domain>  Domain to Target for enumeration.
   -r, &mdash;range       <range>   IP Range for reverse look-up brute force in formats (first-last)</p>

<pre><code>                           or in (range/bitmask).
</code></pre>

<p>   -n, &mdash;name_server <name>    Domain server to use, if none is given the SOA of the</p>

<pre><code>                           target will be used
</code></pre>

<p>   -D, &mdash;dictionary  <file>    Dictionary file of sub-domain and hostnames to use for</p>

<pre><code>                           brute force.
</code></pre>

<p>   -f                          Filter out of Brute Force Domain lookup records that resolve to</p>

<pre><code>                           the wildcard defined IP Address when saving records.
</code></pre>

<p>   -t, &mdash;type        <types>   Specify the type of enumeration to perform:</p>

<pre><code>                           std      To Enumerate general record types, enumerates.
                                    SOA, NS, A, AAAA, MX and SRV if AXRF on the
                                    NS Servers fail.

                           rvl      To Reverse Look Up a given CIDR IP range.

                           brt      To Brute force Domains and Hosts using a given
                                    dictionary.

                           srv      To Enumerate common SRV Records for a given 

                                    domain.

                           axfr     Test all NS Servers in a domain for misconfigured
                                    zone transfers.

                           goo      Perform Google search for sub-domains and hosts.

                           snoop    To Perform a Cache Snooping against all NS 
                                    servers for a given domain, testing all with
                                    file containing the domains, file given with -D
                                    option.

                           tld      Will remove the TLD of given domain and test against
                                    all TLD's registered in IANA

                           zonewalk Will perform a DNSSEC Zone Walk using NSEC Records.
</code></pre>

<p>   -a                          Perform AXFR with the standard enumeration.
   -s                          Perform Reverse Look-up of ipv4 ranges in the SPF Record of the</p>

<pre><code>                           targeted domain with the standard enumeration.
</code></pre>

<p>   -g                          Perform Google enumeration with the standard enumeration.
   -w                          Do deep whois record analysis and reverse look-up of IP</p>

<pre><code>                           ranges found thru whois when doing standard query.
</code></pre>

<p>   -z                          Performs a DNSSEC Zone Walk with the standard enumeration.
   &mdash;threads          <number> Number of threads to use in Range Reverse Look-up, Forward</p>

<pre><code>                           Look-up Brute force and SRV Record Enumeration
</code></pre>

<p>   &mdash;lifetime         <number> Time to wait for a server to response to a query.
   &mdash;db               <file>   SQLite 3 file to save found records.
   &mdash;xml              <file>   XML File to save found records.
   &mdash;iw                        Continua bruteforcing a domain even if a wildcard record resolution is</p>

<pre><code>                           discovered.
</code></pre>

<p>   -c, &mdash;csv          <file>   Comma separated value file.
   -j, &mdash;json         <file>   JSON file.
   -v                          Show attempts in the bruteforce modes.
```</p>

<p><strong>dnsrevenum6</strong></p>

<p>Performs a fast reverse DNS enumeration and is able to cope with slow servers.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dnsrevenum6.png" title="&lsquo;dnsrevenum6&rsquo; &lsquo;dnsrevenum6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnstracer</strong></p>

<p>Determines where a given Domain Name Server (DNS) gets its information from, and follows the chain of DNS servers back to the servers which know the data.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dnstracer.png" title="&lsquo;dnstracer&rsquo; &lsquo;dnstracer&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnswalk</strong></p>

<p>DNS  debugger.  It performs zone transfers of specified domains, and checks the database in numerous ways for internal  consistency,  as well as for correctness according to accepted practices with the Domain Name System.</p>

<p><strong>fierce</strong></p>

<p>Fierce is a semi-lightweight scanner that helps locate non-contiguous
IP space and hostnames against specified domains.  It&rsquo;s really meant
as a pre-cursor to nmap, unicornscan, nessus, nikto, etc, since all
of those require that you already know what IP space you are looking
for.  This does not perform exploitation and does not scan the whole
internet indiscriminately.  It is meant specifically to locate likely
targets both inside and outside a corporate network.  Because it uses
DNS primarily you will often find mis-configured networks that leak
internal address space. That&rsquo;s especially useful in targeted malware.</p>

<p><strong>urlcrazy</strong></p>

<p>Generate and test domain typos and variations to detect and perform typo squatting, URL hijacking,
phishing, and corporate espionage.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/urlcrazy.png" title="&lsquo;urlcrazy&rsquo; &lsquo;urlcrazy&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>IDS/IPS Identification</h3>

<p><strong>fragroute</strong></p>

<p>intercept, modify, and rewrite egress traffic</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/fragroute.png" title="&lsquo;fragroute&rsquo; &lsquo;fragroute&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>fragrouter</strong></p>

<p>network intrusion detection evasion toolkit</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/fragrouter.png" title="&lsquo;fragrouter&rsquo; &lsquo;fragrouter&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>ftest</strong></p>

<p>FTester is a tool designed for testing firewalls filtering policies and Intrusion Detection System (IDS) capabilities.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/ftest.png" title="&lsquo;ftest&rsquo; &lsquo;ftest&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>lbd</strong></p>

<p>load balancing detector &ndash; Checks if a given domain uses load-balancing</p>

<p><strong>wafw00f</strong></p>

<p>Web Application Firewall Detection Tool</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/wafw00f.png" title="&lsquo;wafw00f&rsquo; &lsquo;wafw00f&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Live Host Identification</h3>

<p><strong>alive6</strong></p>

<p>an effective alive scanner, which will detect all systems listening to this address</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/alive6.png" title="&lsquo;alive6&rsquo; &lsquo;alive6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>arping</strong></p>

<p>sends ARP and/or ICMP requests to the specified host and  displays  the  replies.</p>

<p>``` plain
ARPing 2.11, by Thomas Habets <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#116;&#104;&#111;&#x6d;&#97;&#x73;&#64;&#104;&#97;&#x62;&#x65;&#116;&#x73;&#46;&#x73;&#101;">&#116;&#104;&#x6f;&#x6d;&#x61;&#115;&#64;&#x68;&#97;&#98;&#101;&#116;&#115;&#x2e;&#115;&#101;</a>
usage: arping [ -0aAbdDeFpqrRuv ] [ -w <us> ] [ -S <host/ip> ]</p>

<pre><code>          [ -T &lt;host/ip ] [ -s &lt;MAC&gt; ] [ -t &lt;MAC&gt; ] [ -c &lt;count&gt; ]
          [ -i &lt;interface&gt; ] &lt;host/ip/MAC | -B&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Options:</p>

<pre><code>-0     Use this option to ping with source IP address 0.0.0.0. Use this
       when you haven't configured your interface yet.  Note that  this
       may  get  the  MAC-ping  unanswered.   This  is  an alias for -S
       0.0.0.0.
-a     Audiable ping.
-A     Only count addresses matching  requested  address  (This  *WILL*
       break  most things you do. Only useful if you are arpinging many
       hosts at once. See arping-scan-net.sh for an example).
-b     Like -0 but source broadcast source  address  (255.255.255.255).
       Note that this may get the arping unanswered since it's not nor-
       mal behavior for a host.
-B     Use instead of host if you want to address 255.255.255.255.
-c count
       Only send count requests.
-d     Find duplicate replies. Exit with 1 if there are answers from
       two different MAC addresses.
-D     Display answers as exclamation points and missing packets as dots.
-e     Like -a but beep when there is no reply.
-F     Don't try to be smart about the interface name.  (even  if  this
       switch is not given, -i overrides smartness)
-h     Displays a help message and exits.
-i interface
       Use the specified interface.
-q     Does not display messages, except error messages.
-r     Raw output: only the MAC/IP address is displayed for each reply.
-R     Raw output: Like -r but shows "the other one", can  be  combined
       with -r.
-s MAC Set source MAC address. You may need to use -p with this.
-S IP  Like  -b and -0 but with set source address.  Note that this may
       get the arping unanswered if the target does not have routing to
       the  IP.  If you don't own the IP you are using, you may need to
       turn on promiscious mode on the interface (with -p).  With  this
       switch  you can find out what IP-address a host has without tak-
       ing an IP-address yourself.
-t MAC Set target MAC address to use when pinging IP address.
-T IP  Use -T as target address when pinging MACs that won't respond to
       a broadcast ping but perhaps to a directed broadcast.
       Example:
       To check the address of MAC-A, use knowledge of MAC-B and  IP-B.
       $ arping -S &lt;IP-B&gt; -s &lt;MAC-B&gt; -p &lt;MAC-A&gt;
-p     Turn  on  promiscious  mode  on interface, use this if you don't
       "own" the MAC address you are using.
-u     Show index=received/sent instead  of  just  index=received  when
       pinging MACs.
-v     Verbose output. Use twice for more messages.
-w     Time to wait between pings, in microseconds.
</code></pre>

<p>Report bugs to: <a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x74;&#104;&#x6f;&#x6d;&#x61;&#x73;&#64;&#104;&#x61;&#98;&#x65;&#116;&#115;&#46;&#115;&#x65;">&#116;&#104;&#x6f;&#x6d;&#97;&#115;&#x40;&#x68;&#97;&#x62;&#x65;&#116;&#115;&#x2e;&#115;&#x65;</a>
Arping home page: <a href="http://www.habets.pp.se/synscan/">http://www.habets.pp.se/synscan/</a>
Development repo: <a href="http://github.com/ThomasHabets/arping">http://github.com/ThomasHabets/arping</a>
```</p>

<p><strong>cdpsnarf</strong></p>

<p>Cisco Discovery Protocol Sniffer</p>

<p>CDPSnarf is a network sniffer exclusively written to extract
information from CDP packets.
It provides all the information a &ldquo;show cdp neighbors detail&rdquo;
command would return on a Cisco router and even more.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/cdpsnarf.png" title="&lsquo;cdpsnarf&rsquo; &lsquo;cdpsnarf&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>detect-new-ip6</strong></p>

<p>This tool detects new IPv6 addresses joining the local network.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/detect-new-ip6.png" title="&lsquo;detect-new-ip6&rsquo; &lsquo;detect-new-ip6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>detect_sniffer6</strong></p>

<p>Tests if systems on the local LAN are sniffing.
Works against Windows, Linux, OS/X and *BSD
If no target is given, the link-local-all-nodes address is used, which
however not always works.</p>

<p><strong>dmitry</strong></p>

<p>DMitry (Deepmagic Information Gathering Tool) is a UNIX/(GNU)Linux command line application with the ability to gather as much information as possible about a host.</p>

<p>Basic  functionality  of  DMitry  allows for information to be gathered
about a target host from a simple whois lookup on the target to  uptime
reports and TCP portscans.</p>

<p>The application is considered a tool to assist in information gathering
when information is required quickly by removing the need to enter multiple  commands  and  the timely process of searching through data from multiple sources.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/dmitry.png" title="&lsquo;dmitry&rsquo; &lsquo;dmitry&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>dnmap-client</strong> &amp; <strong>dnmap-server</strong></p>

<p>dnmap is a framework to distribute nmap scans among several clients. It reads an already created file with nmap commands and send those commands to each client connected to it. The framework use a client/server architecture. The server knows what to do and the clients do it. All the logic and statistics are managed in the server. Nmap output is stored on both server and client. Usually you would want this if you have to scan a large group of hosts and you have several different internet connections (or friends that want to help you)</p>

<p><code>plain
usage: /usr/bin/dnmap_client &lt;options&gt;
options:
  -s, --server-ip        IP address of dnmap server.
  -p, --server-port      Port of dnmap server. Dnmap port defaults to 46001
  -a, --alias      Your name alias so we can give credit to you for your help. Optional
  -d, --debug      Debuging.
  -m, --max-rate      Force nmaps commands to use at most this rate. Useful to slow nmap down. Adds the --max-rate parameter.
</code></p>

<p>``` plain
usage: /usr/bin/dnmap_server <options>
options:
  -f, &mdash;nmap-commands        Nmap commands file
  -p, &mdash;port        TCP port where we listen for connections.
  -L, &mdash;log-file        Log file. Defaults to /var/log/dnmap_server.conf.
  -l, &mdash;log-level       Log level. Defaults to info.
  -v, &mdash;verbose_level         Verbose level. Give a number between 1 and 5. Defaults to 1. Level 0 means be quiet.
  -t, &mdash;client-timeout         How many time should we wait before marking a client Offline. We still remember its values just in case it cames back.
  -s, &mdash;sort            Field to sort the statical value. You can choose from: Alias, #Commands, UpTime, RunCmdXMin, AvrCmdXMin, Status
  -P, &mdash;pem-file         pem file to use for TLS connection. By default we use the server.pem file provided with the server in the current directory.</p>

<p>dnmap_server uses a &lsquo;&lt;nmap-commands-file-name>.dnmaptrace&rsquo; file to know where it must continue reading the nmap commands file. If you want to start over again,
just delete the &lsquo;&lt;nmap-commands-file-name>.dnmaptrace&rsquo; file
```</p>

<p><strong>fping</strong></p>

<p>send ICMP ECHO_REQUEST packets to network hosts</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/fping.png" title="&lsquo;fping&rsquo; &lsquo;fping&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>hping3</strong></p>

<p>hping3 is a network tool able to send custom TCP/IP packets and to display target replies like ping program does with  ICMP  replies.  hping3 handle  fragmentation,  arbitrary packets body and size and can be used in order to transfer  files  encapsulated  under  supported  protocols.
Using hping3 you are able to perform at least the following stuff:</p>

<ul>
<li>Test firewall rules</li>
<li>Advanced port scanning</li>
<li>Test net performance using different protocols, packet size, TOS (type of service) and fragmentation.</li>
<li>Path MTU discovery</li>
<li>Transferring files between even really fascist firewall rules.</li>
<li>Traceroute-like under different protocols.</li>
<li>Firewalk-like usage.</li>
<li>Remote OS fingerprinting.</li>
<li>TCP/IP stack auditing.</li>
<li>A lot of others.</li>
</ul>


<p>``` plain
usage: hping3 host [options]
  -h  &mdash;help      show this help
  -v  &mdash;version   show version
  -c  &mdash;count     packet count
  -i  &mdash;interval  wait (uX for X microseconds, for example -i u1000)</p>

<pre><code>  --fast      alias for -i u10000 (10 packets for second)
  --faster    alias for -i u1000 (100 packets for second)
  --flood      sent packets as fast as possible. Don't show replies.
</code></pre>

<p>  -n  &mdash;numeric   numeric output
  -q  &mdash;quiet     quiet
  -I  &mdash;interface interface name (otherwise default routing interface)
  -V  &mdash;verbose   verbose mode
  -D  &mdash;debug     debugging info
  -z  &mdash;bind      bind ctrl+z to ttl           (default to dst port)
  -Z  &mdash;unbind    unbind ctrl+z</p>

<pre><code>  --beep      beep for every matching packet received
</code></pre>

<p>Mode
  default mode     TCP
  -0  &mdash;rawip      RAW IP mode
  -1  &mdash;icmp       ICMP mode
  -2  &mdash;udp        UDP mode
  -8  &mdash;scan       SCAN mode.</p>

<pre><code>               Example: hping --scan 1-30,70-90 -S www.target.host
</code></pre>

<p>  -9  &mdash;listen     listen mode
IP
  -a  &mdash;spoof      spoof source address
  &mdash;rand-dest      random destionation address mode. see the man.
  &mdash;rand-source    random source address mode. see the man.
  -t  &mdash;ttl        ttl (default 64)
  -N  &mdash;id         id (default random)
  -W  &mdash;winid      use win* id byte ordering
  -r  &mdash;rel        relativize id field          (to estimate host traffic)
  -f  &mdash;frag       split packets in more frag.  (may pass weak acl)
  -x  &mdash;morefrag   set more fragments flag
  -y  &mdash;dontfrag   set don&rsquo;t fragment flag
  -g  &mdash;fragoff    set the fragment offset
  -m  &mdash;mtu        set virtual mtu, implies &mdash;frag if packet size > mtu
  -o  &mdash;tos        type of service (default 0x00), try &mdash;tos help
  -G  &mdash;rroute     includes RECORD_ROUTE option and display the route buffer
  &mdash;lsrr           loose source routing and record route
  &mdash;ssrr           strict source routing and record route
  -H  &mdash;ipproto    set the IP protocol field, only in RAW IP mode
ICMP
  -C  &mdash;icmptype   icmp type (default echo request)
  -K  &mdash;icmpcode   icmp code (default 0)</p>

<pre><code>  --force-icmp send all icmp types (default send only supported types)
  --icmp-gw    set gateway address for ICMP redirect (default 0.0.0.0)
  --icmp-ts    Alias for --icmp --icmptype 13 (ICMP timestamp)
  --icmp-addr  Alias for --icmp --icmptype 17 (ICMP address subnet mask)
  --icmp-help  display help for others icmp options
</code></pre>

<p>UDP/TCP
  -s  &mdash;baseport   base source port             (default random)
  -p  &mdash;destport   [+][+]<port> destination port(default 0) ctrl+z inc/dec
  -k  &mdash;keep       keep still source port
  -w  &mdash;win        winsize (default 64)
  -O  &mdash;tcpoff     set fake tcp data offset     (instead of tcphdrlen / 4)
  -Q  &mdash;seqnum     shows only tcp sequence number
  -b  &mdash;badcksum   (try to) send packets with a bad IP checksum</p>

<pre><code>               many systems will fix the IP checksum sending the packet
               so you'll get bad UDP/TCP checksum instead.
</code></pre>

<p>  -M  &mdash;setseq     set TCP sequence number
  -L  &mdash;setack     set TCP ack
  -F  &mdash;fin        set FIN flag
  -S  &mdash;syn        set SYN flag
  -R  &mdash;rst        set RST flag
  -P  &mdash;push       set PUSH flag
  -A  &mdash;ack        set ACK flag
  -U  &mdash;urg        set URG flag
  -X  &mdash;xmas       set X unused flag (0x40)
  -Y  &mdash;ymas       set Y unused flag (0x80)
  &mdash;tcpexitcode    use last tcp->th_flags as exit code
  &mdash;tcp-mss        enable the TCP MSS option with the given value
  &mdash;tcp-timestamp  enable the TCP timestamp option to guess the HZ/uptime
Common
  -d  &mdash;data       data size                    (default is 0)
  -E  &mdash;file       data from file
  -e  &mdash;sign       add &lsquo;signature&rsquo;
  -j  &mdash;dump       dump packets in hex
  -J  &mdash;print      dump printable characters
  -B  &mdash;safe       enable &lsquo;safe&rsquo; protocol
  -u  &mdash;end        tell you when &mdash;file reached EOF and prevent rewind
  -T  &mdash;traceroute traceroute mode              (implies &mdash;bind and &mdash;ttl 1)
  &mdash;tr-stop        Exit when receive the first not ICMP in traceroute mode
  &mdash;tr-keep-ttl    Keep the source TTL fixed, useful to monitor just one hop
  &mdash;tr-no-rtt       Don&rsquo;t calculate/show RTT information in traceroute mode
ARS packet description (new, unstable)
  &mdash;apd-send       Send the packet described with APD (see docs/APD.txt)
```</p>

<p><strong>inverse_lookup6</strong></p>

<p>Performs an inverse address query, to get the IPv6 addresses that are assigned
to a MAC address. Note that only few systems support this yet.</p>

<p><strong>miranda</strong></p>

<p>Miranda can discover UPnP hosts either passively or actively, and all of a host’s reported devices types, services, actions and variables can be enumerated with a single command.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/miranda.png" title="&lsquo;miranda&rsquo; &lsquo;miranda&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>ncat</strong></p>

<p>Ncat is a feature-packed networking utility which reads and writes data
across networks from the command line. Ncat was written for the Nmap
Project and is the culmination of the currently splintered family of
Netcat incarnations. It is designed to be a reliable back-end tool to
instantly provide network connectivity to other applications and users.
Ncat will not only work with IPv4 and IPv6 but provides the user with a
virtually limitless number of potential uses.</p>

<p>Among Ncat&rsquo;s vast number of features there is the ability to chain
Ncats together; redirection of TCP, UDP, and SCTP ports to other sites;
SSL support; and proxy connections via SOCKS4 or HTTP proxies (with
optional proxy authentication as well).</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/ncat.png" title="&lsquo;ncat&rsquo; &lsquo;ncat&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>netdiscover</strong></p>

<p>an active/passive arp reconnaissance tool.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/netdiscover.png" title="&lsquo;netdiscover&rsquo; &lsquo;netdiscover&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>passive_discovery6</strong></p>

<p>Passivly sniffs the network and dump all client&rsquo;s IPv6 addresses detected.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/passive_discovery6.png" title="&lsquo;passive_discovery6&rsquo; &lsquo;passive_discovery6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>thcping6</strong></p>

<p>Craft a ICMPv6/TCP/UDP packet with special IPv6 or EH header options.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/thcping6.png" title="&lsquo;thcping6&rsquo; &lsquo;thcping6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>wol-e</strong></p>

<p>WOL-E is a suite of tools for the Wake on LAN feature of network attached computers, this is now enabled by default on many Apple computers. These tools include:</p>

<p>Bruteforcing the MAC address to wake up clients
Sniffing WOL attempts on the network and saving them to disk
Sniffing WOL passwords on the network and saving them to disk
Waking up single clients (post sniffing attack)
Scanning for Apple devices on the network for WOL enabling
Sending bulk WOL requests to all detected Apple clients.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/wol-e.png" title="&lsquo;wol-e&rsquo; &lsquo;wol-e&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>xprobe2</strong></p>

<p>xprobe2 is an active operating system fingerprinting tool with  a  different  approach  to operating system fingerprinting. xprobe2 relies on fuzzy  signature  matching,  probabilistic  guesses,  multiple  matches simultaneously, and a signature database.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/xprobe2.png" title="&lsquo;xprobe2&rsquo; &lsquo;xprobe2&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Network Scanners</h3>

<p><strong>nmap</strong></p>

<p>Nmap (“Network Mapper”) is an open source tool for network exploration
and security auditing. It was designed to rapidly scan large networks,
although it works fine against single hosts. Nmap uses raw IP packets
in novel ways to determine what hosts are available on the network,
what services (application name and version) those hosts are offering,
what operating systems (and OS versions) they are running, what type of
packet filters/firewalls are in use, and dozens of other
characteristics. While Nmap is commonly used for security audits, many
systems and network administrators find it useful for routine tasks
such as network inventory, managing service upgrade schedules, and
monitoring host or service uptime.</p>

<p>``` plain
Nmap 6.47 ( <a href="http://nmap.org">http://nmap.org</a> )
Usage: nmap [Scan Type(s)] [Options] {target specification}
TARGET SPECIFICATION:
  Can pass hostnames, IP addresses, networks, etc.
  Ex: scanme.nmap.org, microsoft.com/24, 192.168.0.1; 10.0.0-255.1-254
  -iL <inputfilename>: Input from list of hosts/networks
  -iR <num hosts>: Choose random targets
  &mdash;exclude &lt;host1[,host2][,host3],&hellip;>: Exclude hosts/networks
  &mdash;excludefile &lt;exclude_file>: Exclude list from file
HOST DISCOVERY:
  -sL: List Scan &ndash; simply list targets to scan
  -sn: Ping Scan &ndash; disable port scan
  -Pn: Treat all hosts as online &mdash; skip host discovery
  -PS/PA/PU/PY[portlist]: TCP SYN/ACK, UDP or SCTP discovery to given ports
  -PE/PP/PM: ICMP echo, timestamp, and netmask request discovery probes
  -PO[protocol list]: IP Protocol Ping
  -n/-R: Never do DNS resolution/Always resolve [default: sometimes]
  &mdash;dns-servers &lt;serv1[,serv2],&hellip;>: Specify custom DNS servers
  &mdash;system-dns: Use OS&rsquo;s DNS resolver
  &mdash;traceroute: Trace hop path to each host
SCAN TECHNIQUES:
  -sS/sT/sA/sW/sM: TCP SYN/Connect()/ACK/Window/Maimon scans
  -sU: UDP Scan
  -sN/sF/sX: TCP Null, FIN, and Xmas scans
  &mdash;scanflags <flags>: Customize TCP scan flags
  -sI <zombie host[:probeport]>: Idle scan
  -sY/sZ: SCTP INIT/COOKIE-ECHO scans
  -sO: IP protocol scan
  -b <FTP relay host>: FTP bounce scan
PORT SPECIFICATION AND SCAN ORDER:
  -p <port ranges>: Only scan specified ports</p>

<pre><code>Ex: -p22; -p1-65535; -p U:53,111,137,T:21-25,80,139,8080,S:9
</code></pre>

<p>  -F: Fast mode &ndash; Scan fewer ports than the default scan
  -r: Scan ports consecutively &ndash; don&rsquo;t randomize
  &mdash;top-ports <number>: Scan <number> most common ports
  &mdash;port-ratio <ratio>: Scan ports more common than <ratio>
SERVICE/VERSION DETECTION:
  -sV: Probe open ports to determine service/version info
  &mdash;version-intensity <level>: Set from 0 (light) to 9 (try all probes)
  &mdash;version-light: Limit to most likely probes (intensity 2)
  &mdash;version-all: Try every single probe (intensity 9)
  &mdash;version-trace: Show detailed version scan activity (for debugging)
SCRIPT SCAN:
  -sC: equivalent to &mdash;script=default
  &mdash;script=<Lua scripts>: <Lua scripts> is a comma separated list of</p>

<pre><code>       directories, script-files or script-categories
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;script-args=&lt;n1=v1,[n2=v2,&hellip;]>: provide arguments to scripts
  &mdash;script-args-file=filename: provide NSE script args in a file
  &mdash;script-trace: Show all data sent and received
  &mdash;script-updatedb: Update the script database.
  &mdash;script-help=<Lua scripts>: Show help about scripts.</p>

<pre><code>       &lt;Lua scripts&gt; is a comma-separated list of script-files or
       script-categories.
</code></pre>

<p>OS DETECTION:
  -O: Enable OS detection
  &mdash;osscan-limit: Limit OS detection to promising targets
  &mdash;osscan-guess: Guess OS more aggressively
TIMING AND PERFORMANCE:
  Options which take <time> are in seconds, or append &lsquo;ms&rsquo; (milliseconds),
  &rsquo;s' (seconds), &rsquo;m' (minutes), or &lsquo;h&rsquo; (hours) to the value (e.g. 30m).
  -T&lt;0-5>: Set timing template (higher is faster)
  &mdash;min-hostgroup/max-hostgroup <size>: Parallel host scan group sizes
  &mdash;min-parallelism/max-parallelism <numprobes>: Probe parallelization
  &mdash;min-rtt-timeout/max-rtt-timeout/initial-rtt-timeout <time>: Specifies</p>

<pre><code>  probe round trip time.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;max-retries <tries>: Caps number of port scan probe retransmissions.
  &mdash;host-timeout <time>: Give up on target after this long
  &mdash;scan-delay/&mdash;max-scan-delay <time>: Adjust delay between probes
  &mdash;min-rate <number>: Send packets no slower than <number> per second
  &mdash;max-rate <number>: Send packets no faster than <number> per second
FIREWALL/IDS EVASION AND SPOOFING:
  -f; &mdash;mtu <val>: fragment packets (optionally w/given MTU)
  -D &lt;decoy1,decoy2[,ME],&hellip;>: Cloak a scan with decoys
  -S &lt;IP_Address>: Spoof source address
  -e <iface>: Use specified interface
  -g/&mdash;source-port <portnum>: Use given port number
  &mdash;proxies &lt;url1,[url2],&hellip;>: Relay connections through HTTP/SOCKS4 proxies
  &mdash;data-length <num>: Append random data to sent packets
  &mdash;ip-options <options>: Send packets with specified ip options
  &mdash;ttl <val>: Set IP time-to-live field
  &mdash;spoof-mac <mac address/prefix/vendor name>: Spoof your MAC address
  &mdash;badsum: Send packets with a bogus TCP/UDP/SCTP checksum
OUTPUT:
  -oN/-oX/-oS/-oG <file>: Output scan in normal, XML, s|&lt;rIpt kIddi3,</p>

<pre><code> and Grepable format, respectively, to the given filename.
</code></pre>

<p>  -oA <basename>: Output in the three major formats at once
  -v: Increase verbosity level (use -vv or more for greater effect)
  -d: Increase debugging level (use -dd or more for greater effect)
  &mdash;reason: Display the reason a port is in a particular state
  &mdash;open: Only show open (or possibly open) ports
  &mdash;packet-trace: Show all packets sent and received
  &mdash;iflist: Print host interfaces and routes (for debugging)
  &mdash;log-errors: Log errors/warnings to the normal-format output file
  &mdash;append-output: Append to rather than clobber specified output files
  &mdash;resume <filename>: Resume an aborted scan
  &mdash;stylesheet <path/URL>: XSL stylesheet to transform XML output to HTML
  &mdash;webxml: Reference stylesheet from Nmap.Org for more portable XML
  &mdash;no-stylesheet: Prevent associating of XSL stylesheet w/XML output
MISC:
  -6: Enable IPv6 scanning
  -A: Enable OS detection, version detection, script scanning, and traceroute
  &mdash;datadir <dirname>: Specify custom Nmap data file location
  &mdash;send-eth/&mdash;send-ip: Send using raw ethernet frames or IP packets
  &mdash;privileged: Assume that the user is fully privileged
  &mdash;unprivileged: Assume the user lacks raw socket privileges
  -V: Print version number
  -h: Print this help summary page.
EXAMPLES:
  nmap -v -A scanme.nmap.org
  nmap -v -sn 192.168.0.0/16 10.0.0.0/8
  nmap -v -iR 10000 -Pn -p 80
SEE THE MAN PAGE (<a href="http://nmap.org/book/man.html">http://nmap.org/book/man.html</a>) FOR MORE OPTIONS AND EXAMPLES
```</p>

<p><strong>unicornscan</strong></p>

<p>asynchronous network stimulus delivery/response recoring tool.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/unicornscan.png" title="&lsquo;unicornscan&rsquo; &lsquo;unicornscan&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>zenmap</strong></p>

<p>Zenmap is a multi-platform graphical Nmap frontend and results viewer.
Zenmap aims to make Nmap easy for beginners to use while giving
experienced Nmap users advanced features. Frequently used scans can be
saved as profiles to make them easy to run repeatedly. A command
creator allows interactive creation of Nmap command lines. Scan results
can be saved and viewed later. Saved scan results can be compared with
one another to see how they differ. The results of recent scans are
stored in a searchable database.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/zenmap.png" title="&lsquo;zenmap&rsquo; &lsquo;zenmap&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>OS Fingerprinting</h3>

<p>Covered in the above</p>

<h3>OSINT Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>casefile</strong></p>

<p>CaseFile is the little brother to Maltego. It targets a unique market of &lsquo;offline&rsquo; analysts whose primary sources of information are not gained from the open-source intelligence side or can be programmatically queried. We see these people as investigators and analysts who are working &lsquo;on the ground&rsquo;, getting intelligence from other people in the team and building up an information map of their investigation.</p>

<p>CaseFile gives you the ability to quickly add, link and analyze data having the same graphing flexibility and performance as Maltego without the use of transforms.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/casefile.png" title="&lsquo;casefile&rsquo; &lsquo;casefile&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>creepy</strong></p>

<p>creepy  is an application that allows you to gather geolocation related
information about users from  social  networking  platforms  and  image
hosting  services.  The  information  is  presented in a map inside the
application where all the retrieved data is shown accompanied with relevant information (i.e. what was posted from that specific location) to
provide context to the presentation.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/creepy.png" title="&lsquo;creepy&rsquo; &lsquo;creepy&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>jigsaw</strong></p>

<p>Email harvesting, can search on jigsaw.com</p>

<p><strong>maltego</strong></p>

<p>Maltego is a program that can be used to determine the relationships and real world links between:</p>

<p>People</p>

<p>Groups of people (social networks)</p>

<p>Companies</p>

<p>Organizations</p>

<p>Web sites</p>

<p>Internet infrastructure such as:</p>

<p>Domains</p>

<p>DNS names</p>

<p>Netblocks</p>

<p>IP addresses</p>

<p>Phrases</p>

<p>Affiliations</p>

<p>Documents and files</p>

<p>These entities are linked using open source intelligence.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/maltego.png" title="&lsquo;maltego&rsquo; &lsquo;maltego&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>metagoofil</strong></p>

<p>Metagoofil is an information gathering tool designed for extracting metadata of public documents (pdf,doc,xls,ppt,docx,pptx,xlsx) belonging to a target company.</p>

<p>Metagoofil will perform a search in Google to identify and download the documents to local disk and then will extract the metadata with different libraries like Hachoir, PdfMiner? and others. With the results it will generate a report with usernames, software versions and servers or machine names that will help Penetration testers in the information gathering phase.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/maltego.png" title="&lsquo;metagoofil&rsquo; &lsquo;metagoofil&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>recon-ng</strong></p>

<p>Recon-ng is a full-featured Web Reconnaissance framework written in Python. Complete with independent modules, database interaction, built in convenience functions, interactive help, and command completion, Recon-ng provides a powerful environment in which open source web-based reconnaissance can be conducted quickly and thoroughly.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/recon-ng.png" title="&lsquo;recon-ng&rsquo; &lsquo;recon-ng&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>theharvester</strong></p>

<p>The objective of this program is to gather emails, subdomains, hosts, employee names, open ports and banners from different public sources like search engines, PGP key servers and SHODAN computer database.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/theharvester.png" title="&lsquo;theharvester&rsquo; &lsquo;theharvester&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>twofi</strong></p>

<p>Twitter Words Of Interest</p>

<p>Build a custom wordlist based on Twitter keywords</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/twofi.png" title="&lsquo;twofi&rsquo; &lsquo;twofi&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Route analysis</h3>

<p><strong>0trace</strong></p>

<p>Trace route to target</p>

<p><strong>intrace</strong></p>

<p>InTrace is a traceroute-like application that enables users to enumerate IP hops exploiting existing TCP connections, both initiated from local network (local system) or from remote hosts.</p>

<p><strong>netmask</strong></p>

<p>This  program  accepts and produces a variety of common network address
and netmask formats.  Not only can it convert address and netmask notations,  but it will optimize the masks to generate the smallest list of
rules.  This is very handy if you&rsquo;ve  ever  configured  a  firewall  or
router  and  some  nasty  network administrator before you decided that
base 10 numbers were good places to start and end groups of machines.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/netmask.png" title="&lsquo;netmask&rsquo; &lsquo;netmask&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>trace6</strong></p>

<p>A basic but very fast traceroute6 program.
If no port is specified, ICMP6 Ping requests are used, otherwise TCP SYN
packets to the specified port.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/trace6.png" title="&lsquo;trace6&rsquo; &lsquo;trace6&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Service Fingerprinting</h3>

<p><strong>implementation6</strong></p>

<p>Performs some IPv6 implementation checks, can be used to test some
firewall features too. Takes approx. 2 minutes to complete.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/implementation6.png" title="&lsquo;implementation6&rsquo; &lsquo;implementation6&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>implementation6d</strong></p>

<p>Identifies test packets by the implementation6 tool, useful to check what
packets passed a firewall</p>

<p><strong>sslscan</strong></p>

<p>SSLScan is a fast SSL port scanner. SSLScan connects to SSL
ports and determines what  ciphers are supported, which are
the servers  preferred  ciphers,  which  SSL  protocols  are
supported  and   returns  the   SSL   certificate.   Client
certificates /  private key can be configured and output is
to text / XML.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslscan.png" title="&lsquo;sslscan&rsquo; &lsquo;sslscan&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sslyze</strong></p>

<p>SSLyze is a Python tool that can analyze the SSL configuration of a server by connecting to it. It is designed to be fast and comprehensive, and should help organizations and testers identify misconfigurations affecting their SSL servers.</p>

<p>``` plain
Usage: sslyze [options] target1.com target2.com:443 etc&hellip;</p>

<p>Options:
  &mdash;version             show program&rsquo;s version number and exit
  -h, &mdash;help            show this help message and exit
  &mdash;xml_out=XML_FILE    Writes the scan results as an XML document to the file</p>

<pre><code>                    XML_FILE.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;targets_in=TARGETS_IN</p>

<pre><code>                    Reads the list of targets to scan from the file
                    TARGETS_IN. It should contain one host:port per line.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;timeout=TIMEOUT     Sets the timeout value in seconds used for every</p>

<pre><code>                    socket connection made to the target server(s).
                    Default is 5s.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;https_tunnel=HTTPS_TUNNEL</p>

<pre><code>                    Sets an HTTP CONNECT proxy to tunnel SSL traffic to
                    the target server(s). HTTP_TUNNEL should be
                    'host:port'. Requires Python 2.7
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;starttls=STARTTLS   Identifies the target server(s) as a SMTP or an XMPP</p>

<pre><code>                    server(s) and scans the server(s) using STARTTLS.
                    STARTTLS should be 'smtp' or 'xmpp'.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;xmpp_to=XMPP_TO     Optional setting for STARTTLS XMPP.  XMPP_TO should be</p>

<pre><code>                    the hostname to be put in the 'to' attribute of the
                    XMPP stream. Default is the server's hostname.
</code></pre>

<p>  &mdash;regular             Regular HTTPS scan; shortcut for &mdash;sslv2 &mdash;sslv3</p>

<pre><code>                    --tlsv1 --reneg --resum --certinfo --http_get
                    --hide_rejected_ciphers --compression --tlsv1_1
                    --tlsv1_2
</code></pre>

<p>  Client certificate support:</p>

<pre><code>--cert=CERT         Client certificate filename.
--certform=CERTFORM
                    Client certificate format. DER or PEM (default).
--key=KEY           Client private key filename.
--keyform=KEYFORM   Client private key format. DER or PEM (default).
--pass=KEYPASS      Client private key passphrase.
</code></pre>

<p>  PluginOpenSSLCipherSuites:</p>

<pre><code>Scans the target server for supported OpenSSL cipher suites.

--sslv2             Lists the SSL 2.0 OpenSSL cipher suites supported by
                    the server.
--sslv3             Lists the SSL 3.0 OpenSSL cipher suites supported by
                    the server.
--tlsv1             Lists the TLS 1.0 OpenSSL cipher suites supported by
                    the server.
--tlsv1_1           Lists the TLS 1.1 OpenSSL cipher suites supported by
                    the server.
--tlsv1_2           Lists the TLS 1.2 OpenSSL cipher suites supported by
                    the server.
--http_get          Option - For each cipher suite, sends an HTTP GET
                    request after completing the SSL handshake and returns
                    the HTTP status code.
--hide_rejected_ciphers
                    Option - Hides the (usually long) list of cipher
                    suites that were rejected by the server.
</code></pre>

<p>  PluginCertInfo:</p>

<pre><code>--certinfo=CERTINFO
                    Verifies the target server's certificate validity
                    against Mozilla's trusted root store, and prints
                    relevant fields of the certificate. CERTINFO should be
                    'basic' or 'full'.
</code></pre>

<p>  PluginSessionRenegotiation:</p>

<pre><code>--reneg             Tests the target server's support for client-initiated
                    renegotiations and secure renegotiations.
</code></pre>

<p>  PluginCompression:</p>

<pre><code>--compression       Tests the server for Zlib compression support.
</code></pre>

<p>  PluginSessionResumption:</p>

<pre><code>Analyzes the target server's SSL session resumption capabilities.

--resum             Tests the server for session ressumption support,
                    using session IDs and TLS session tickets (RFC 5077).
--resum_rate        Performs 100 session resumptions with the target
                    server, in order to estimate the session resumption
                    rate.
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p><strong>tlssled</strong></p>

<p>ssl tls scanner</p>

<h3>SMB Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>acccheck</strong></p>

<p>Attempts to connect to the IPC$ and ADMIN$ shares depending on which flags have been
chosen, and tries a combination of usernames and passwords in the hope to identify
the password to a given account via a dictionary password guessing attack.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/acccheck.png" title="&lsquo;acccheck&rsquo; &lsquo;acccheck&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>nbtscan</strong></p>

<p>nbtscan is a program for scanning IP networks for NetBIOS name information.  It  sends NetBIOS status query to each address in supplied range and lists  received  information  in  human  readable  form.  For  each responded  host  it  lists IP address, NetBIOS computer name, logged-in user name and MAC address (such as Ethernet).</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/nbtscan.png" title="&lsquo;nbtscan&rsquo; &lsquo;nbtscan&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>SMTP Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>smtp-user-enum</strong></p>

<p>Username guessing tool primarily for use against the default Solaris SMTP service. Can use either EXPN, VRFY or RCPT TO</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/smtp-user-enum.png" title="&lsquo;smtp-user-enum&rsquo; &lsquo;smtp-user-enum&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>swaks</strong></p>

<p>Swiss Army Knife SMTP, the all-purpose smtp transaction tester</p>

<p>swaks' primary design goal is to be a flexible, scriptable,
transaction-oriented SMTP test tool.  It handles SMTP features and
extensions such as TLS, authentication, and pipelining; multiple
version of the SMTP protocol including SMTP, ESMTP, and LMTP; and
multiple transport methods including unix-domain sockets, internet-
domain sockets, and pipes to spawned processes.  Options can be
specified in environment variables, configuration files, and the
command line allowing maximum configurability and ease of use for
operators and scripters.</p>

<h3>SNMP Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>braa</strong></p>

<p>Braa is a tool for making SNMP queries. It is able to query hundreds or thousands of hosts simultaneously, while being completely single-threaded. It does not need any SNMP libraries, as it is equipped with its own SNMP engine</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/braa.png" title="&lsquo;braa&rsquo; &lsquo;braa&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>cisco-auditing-tool</strong></p>

<p>Perl script which scans cisco routers for common vulnerabilities. Checks for default passwords, easily guessable community names, and the IOS history bug. Includes support for plugins and scanning multiple hosts.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/cisco-auditing-tool.png" title="&lsquo;cisco-auditing-tool&rsquo; &lsquo;cisco-auditing-tool&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>cisco-torch</strong></p>

<p>mass scanning, application layer fingerprinting, and exploitation tool to discover and attack remote Cisco hosts running Telnet, SSH, Web, TFTP, NTP and SNMP services. Useful in auditing large networks for misconfigured/un-updated Ciscos.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/cisco-torch.png" title="&lsquo;cisco-torch&rsquo; &lsquo;cisco-torch&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>copy-router-config</strong></p>

<p>copy an entire router configuration file from a Cisco device</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/copy-router-config.png" title="&lsquo;copy-router-config&rsquo; &lsquo;copy-router-config&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>merge-router-config</strong></p>

<p>make changes to a Cisco router configuration file and merge those changes to a Cisco router</p>

<p><strong>onesixtyone</strong></p>

<p>simple SNMP scanner which sends requests for the  sys‐Descr value asynchronously with user-adjustable sending times.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/onesixtyone.png" title="&lsquo;onesixtyone&rsquo; &lsquo;onesixtyone&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>snmpcheck</strong></p>

<p>SNMP device enumerator</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/snmpcheck.png" title="&lsquo;snmpcheck&rsquo; &lsquo;snmpcheck&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>SSL Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>sslcaudit</strong></p>

<p>This tool is designed to automate testing SSL/TLS clients for resistance against MITM attacks</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslcaudit.png" title="&lsquo;sslcaudit&rsquo; &lsquo;sslcaudit&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>ssldump</strong></p>

<p>ssldump is an SSL/TLS network protocol analyzer. It identifies TCP connections on the chosen network interface and attempts to interpret them as  SSL/TLS traffic. When it identifies SSL/TLS traffic, it decodes the records and displays them in a textual form to stdout. If provided with the  appropriate  keying material, it will also decrypt the connections and display the application data traffic.</p>

<p><strong>sslh</strong></p>

<p>ssl/ssh multiplexer</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslh.png" title="&lsquo;sslh&rsquo; &lsquo;sslh&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sslsniff</strong></p>

<p>sslsniff  is  designed  to  create man-in-the-middle (MITM) attacks for
SSL/TLS connections, and dynamically generates certs  for  the  domains
that  are  being  accessed  on  the  fly. The new certificates are constructed in a certificate chain that is signed by any certificate  that is provided.
sslsniff  also  supports other attacks like null-prefix or OCSP attacks
to achieve silent interceptions of connections when possible.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslsniff.png" title="&lsquo;sslsniff&rsquo; &lsquo;sslsniff&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sslsplit</strong></p>

<p>SSLsplit  is  a  tool  for  man-in-the-middle  attacks  against SSL/TLS
encrypted network connections.  Connections  are  transparently  intercepted  through  a network address translation engine and redirected to
SSLsplit.  SSLsplit terminates SSL/TLS and initiates a new SSL/TLS connection  to  the  original  destination address, while logging all data
transmitted.  SSLsplit is intended to be useful for  network  forensics
and penetration testing.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslsplit.png" title="&lsquo;sslsplit&rsquo; &lsquo;sslsplit&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>sslstrip</strong></p>

<p>SSL/TLS man-in-the-middle attack tool</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/sslstrip.png" title="&lsquo;sslstrip&rsquo; &lsquo;sslstrip&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>stunnel</strong></p>

<p>The stunnel program is designed to work as SSL encryption wrapper
between remote clients and local (inetd-startable) or remote servers.
The concept is that having non-SSL aware daemons running on your system
you can easily set them up to communicate with clients over secure SSL channels.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/stunnel.png" title="&lsquo;stunnel&rsquo; &lsquo;stunnel&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Telephony Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>ace</strong></p>

<p>Automated Corporate (Data) Enumerator</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/ace.png" title="&lsquo;ace&rsquo; &lsquo;ace&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Traffic Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>irpas-ass</strong></p>

<p>Autonomous System Scanner</p>

<p><strong>irpass-cdp</strong></p>

<p>This program is for sending CDP (Cisco router Discovery Protocol) messages to the wire.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/irpass-cdp.png" title="&lsquo;irpass-cdp&rsquo; &lsquo;irpass-cdp&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>p0f</strong></p>

<p>P0f is a tool that utilizes an array of sophisticated, purely passive traffic
fingerprinting mechanisms to identify the players behind any incidental TCP/IP
communications (often as little as a single normal SYN) without interfering in
any way.</p>

<p>Some of its capabilities include:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Highly scalable and extremely fast identification of the operating system
and software on both endpoints of a vanilla TCP connection &ndash; especially in
settings where NMap probes are blocked, too slow, unreliable, or would
simply set off alarms,</p></li>
<li><p>Measurement of system uptime and network hookup, distance (including
topology behind NAT or packet filters), and so on.</p></li>
<li><p>Automated detection of connection sharing / NAT, load balancing, and
application-level proxying setups.</p></li>
<li><p>Detection of dishonest clients / servers that forge declarative statements
such as X-Mailer or User-Agent.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/p0f.png" title="&lsquo;p0f&rsquo; &lsquo;p0f&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>tcpflow</strong></p>

<p>tcpflow is a program that captures data transmitted as part of TCP connections (flows), and stores the data in a way that is convenient for protocol analysis or debugging.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/tcpflow.png" title="&lsquo;tcpflow&rsquo; &lsquo;tcpflow&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>wireshark</strong></p>

<p>Wireshark is a GUI network protocol analyzer.  It lets you
interactively browse packet data from a live network or from a
previously saved capture file.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/wireshark.png" title="&lsquo;wireshark&rsquo; &lsquo;wireshark&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>VoIP Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>enumiax</strong></p>

<p>enumIAX is an Inter Asterisk Exchange version 2 (IAX2) protocol username brute-force enumerator.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kali/recon/enumiax.png" title="&lsquo;enumiax&rsquo; &lsquo;enumiax&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>VPN Analysis</h3>

<p><strong>ike-scan</strong></p>

<p>Discover and fingerprint IKE hosts (IPsec VPN servers)</p>

<p>``` plain
Target hosts must be specified on the command line unless the &mdash;file option is
given, in which case the targets are read from the specified file instead.</p>

<p>The target hosts can be specified as IP addresses or hostnames.  You can also
specify IPnetwork/bits (e.g. 192.168.1.0/24) to specify all hosts in the given
network (network and broadcast addresses included), and IPstart-IPend
(e.g. 192.168.1.3-192.168.1.27) to specify all hosts in the inclusive range.</p>

<p>These different options for specifying target hosts may be used both on the
command line, and also in the file specified with the &mdash;file option.
```</p>

<p>Ok, that took forever. I will make posts with the other categories as well.</p>

<blockquote><p>The only way to keep your health is to eat what you don&rsquo;t want, drink what
you don&rsquo;t like, and do what you&rsquo;d rather not.</p>

<p>&mdash; Mark Twain</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
